斯坦福大学
Stanford University.
欢迎来到CS193P课程 2013-14秋季第14讲
Welcome to the lecture 14 of CS193P for Fall of 2013 and 14.
今天我将讲到一些比较杂的主题
Today I'm going to talk a little bit about miscellaneous topics,
UIApplication和网络活动指示器
UI application and network activity indicator,
然后我打算继续上次的demo
and then I'm going to follow up a little bit on the demo we did last time,
我要接着上周创建的Photomania程序
then I'm going to continue that demo, and we're going to take Photo Mania
让它运行到iPad上
that we built last week and we're going to make it work on the iPad,
我还要给它加个弹窗segue
and we're going to add a popover segue to it,
因为几周前我讲过弹窗
because I talked about popovers a couple weeks ago,
但我从来就没演示过
but I never showed you how to do it, and you know, all this stuff
要知道 我不能只是讲而不演示
if I just tell you about it, it's really not real probably
否则你们会一头雾水 这里我要演示弹窗
for you until I show you how to do it, so we'll do a popover.
然后我们将开始讨论地图
And then we're going to dive into maps,
今天的课将开始讨论地图
so I'll be doing the lecture today on maps.
但愿我能讲完
Hopefully, I'll get all the way through it.
然后周三 我会做一个地图的demo
And then on Wednesday, I will do a demo with the maps,
周三我还将演示更多segue 特别是embed segue
and also then on Wednesday, I will demo some more segues, especially the embed segue.
这就是我们的安排
So that's what we're talking about today.
首先讲一些比较杂的主题
So let's talk about a couple of miscellaneous topics.
第一个是UIApplication
So UI application is my first one.
什么是UIApplication
What is UI application?
听起来很重要
It sounds important.
其实并没有那么重要
It's not really that important, we dive right
上周我们使用了应用委托
into using the application delegate last week, where we did things like application,
包括didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
did finish launching with options and,
处理后台进入的URL
you know, handling background URLs coming in,
后台取回 等等
and background fetching and all that.
这些都是应用委托
That was all in the applications delegate.
应用委托实际上是由另一个对象上的属性所设置
So the applications delegate is actually set by a property on another
这就是UIApplication
object called UI application.
UIApplication这个类
So UI application, this class,
在整个应用中只有一个实例
it only has one instance in your entire application.
通过这个调用 UIApplication sharedApplication
You get it by calling this UI application shared application,
这个里面没有太多有趣的东西
and there's really not a lot of really interesting stuff
你可以自己去看说明文档
in this thing, you can go check out the documentation,
实际的东西都在应用委托中
but all the real stuff is in applications delegate.
应用上有一个属性 叫委托
Alright? So it has a property on your application called delegate,
它会自动为你设置
that gets automatically set for you,
然后是你的应用委托对象 上周三我们详细看过
and then your application delegate object, which we did a lot in last Wednesday,
所有动作都在这里
that's where all the action is.
你可以自己去看UIApplication
So you can check out UI application if you want.
不过我想指出UIApplication上的一个特定属性
I did want to point out one particular property on UI application, however,
也就是networkActivityIndicatorVisible属性
which is the network activity indicator visible property.
这是一个布尔型属性
This is a Boolean property.
如果设为YES 那么状态栏上的那个小转轮就会转
If you set it to yes, then the little spinner that shows
见过吗
up on the status bar, have you ever seen that?
进行网络活动时 有个小转轮在转
When you're doing network stuff, there's a little spinner that's spinning,
应用是活动应用时 这个会开启
that turns that on when your application is the active application.
这个是布尔型的 YES或NO 转轮对应开或关
And this thing, you know, it's Boolean, yes or no, that spinner is either on or it's off,
它的开关完全取决于你
it's totally your responsibility to turn this thing on and off.
这有点难于处理 因为
It's a little bit difficult to deal with because
一 它是全局的 它在UIApplication中
A, it's global, it's in UI application,
你的应用中的所有线程都在使用这个转轮
so all the threads in your application are all using this same spinner,
二是 它是一个布尔型 而不是压入弹出 或是计数
and number two, it's a Boolean, it's not like a push and pop or a count,
假设你开始了一个很大的Flickr取回 需要10秒
and so imagine that you fire off a big Flickr fetch that's going to take ten seconds.
你开始app
And you start the app,
这个网络活动指示器 打开为YES
this network activity indicator, turn it to yes.
然后在另一个线程中 你发起了一个小的Flickr取回
Then, in another thread, you fire off a little Flickr fetch,
只需要1秒钟
it's only going to take one second.
它发起了 打开了这个 1秒钟过去
So it fires off, it turns this on, one second goes on,
它完成了 然后关掉
it finishes, it turns it back off.
现在它关掉了 但10秒那个还在运行
Now it's off, but the ten second one is still running.
这就糟糕了
So that's bad.
很不幸 你需要在app中添加一些机制
So it's totally up to you, unfortunately, to put mechanism in your app for dealing
来处理这里API的过分简单化
with that unfortunate simplicity of API.
我不确定 不过我猜
I'm sure, I mean, I don't know, but I'm guessing
苹果试过在这上面加一些复杂的API
that Apple tried to put more complicated API on top of this,
但这并不适用于人们在不同线程
and it just didn't work for all different kinds of ways people,
进行各种网络活动的不同需要
you know, are doing network activity in different threads,
最后他们只能说 这个还是留给你们自己吧
so they just kind of said, okay we'll give you this and we'll leave it to you.
不过 你应该开启这个
But you should turn this on.
我不确定苹果会不会因为某个程序没有开启这个
I'm not sure if Apple would reject an application submitted
而拒绝它在App商店中的提交
to the App Store that didn't turn this on,
不过他们很有可能这么做
and did do network activity, but they might.
而且这样做在他们的权利范围之内
And they'd probably be within their rights to doing it.
为什么要这个呢
Why do we have this thing?
因为很多用户都在使用移动电话
Because a lot of users might be on cellular,
他们可能一个月只有300兆流量
and they only have 300 megabytes a month or something,
他们希望知道应用什么时候在耗流量
and they want to know when apps are using that up, right?
他们希望看到那个旋转
So they want to see that little thing spinning.
因此 开启这个非常重要
So that's why it's important to turn this thing on.
这是网络活动的转轮 而不是请等待的转轮
Only when you're doing network activity, this is not a spinner for please wait, okay.
首先 app不应该总让用户等
Your app first of all should never be doing please wait,
因为一切都可以不在主线程上进行
because as we know, we do everything off the main thread,
不过这里是告诉用户 网络活动正在发生
but this is just to tell them network activity is happening,
哪怕是在app的后台
even in the background in my app.
有问题
Question back there?
问题是iOS难道不能知道
Yeah, so the question is can't iOS know
我的app在进行网络活动 然后为我开启吗
that I'm doing network activity in my app and turn it on for me?
答案它大多数时候都能知道
And the answer is, I'll be it could figure it out most of the time,
但并非100%的时候
but not 100 percent of the time,
因为你在网络活动时
because when you do a network activity,
你会发起什么东西 或许是URLSession
you fire something off, maybe you're doing that URL session,
等等 如果是URLSession
things like that, I think if you do the URL session
这个发生时 iOS应该会开启它
where it's actually happening I bet they do turn it on, or they might.
具体我不知道
I really don't know what they do,
不过可以肯定的是 这不是100%可靠的
but then the bottom line is they can't reliably 100 percent do
因此他们要求你来做
it, so they're asking you, you can do it here.
据我所知 情况就是这样的
This is the best to my knowledge, that's the answer.
以上只是一些离题的话
Um, okay so that was just a little aside.
下面 我们将接着上周三的demo来
So now, a little follow up on our demo that we did last Wednesday.
有两点我要澄清 我也确实澄清了
Two things that I want to clarify and that I did clarify
下载了已发布代码 读了评论的人知道
if you downloaded the posted code and read the comments,
一点是 有时我在demo中途
one is, as I was going through my demo,
忘记了一些东西 例如我忘了这一段代码
sometimes I forget things, and I did forget this one line of code,
也就是如果你想让这些后台取回发生
which is you have to send a message if you want to get these background
你就需要发送一条消息给你的共享应用
fetches to happen, to your shared application,
消息叫作setMinimumBackgroundFetchInterval
you shared your application called set minimum background fetch interval.
这个区间是NSTimeInterval
So that interval, and it's NS time interval,
以秒数计
it's the number of seconds
是iOS给你机会进行后台取回的最小时间间隔
that is the minimum between the times that iOS will send you the opportunity
to do a background fetch, right?
这时你在后台
So you're in the background, remember,
iOS会发个消息给你说 嘿 醒醒
the iOS can send you a thing, it says "Hey, wake up,
你现在可以进行后台取回 而这里是最小值
you can do a background fetch if you want," and this says the minimum.
这个最小值 你甚至可以设为1秒 每秒都唤醒
Now, this minimum, you can't set it to one second, it's going to wake you up every second
因为有一个UIApplicationBackgroundFetchIntervalMinimum
because there's a UI application background fetch interval
这就是你可以设置的最小值
minimum and that's the minimum you can set it to,
如果设置为这个
and so if you want to set it to that,
系统就会尽可能多地将你唤醒
then you'll get woken up as much as the system is willing to wake you up,
记住 这只是最小值
remember that only the minimum.
唤醒你可能会需要更久 取决于发生了什么
It could take much longer to wake you up, depending on what's happening.
关于这些后台取回有一点要讲
One thing about these background fetches,
系统在何时唤醒你进行后台取回方面非常聪明
the system is quite smart about when it wakes you up to do a background fetch,
它可能也会唤醒其它一些程序 进行后台取回
it's probably waking up a whole bunch of other apps doing background fetches too,
一次性做所有这些事 因为
and doing it all at one time because all
iOS中的所有这些多任务处理 都是为了节约电量
of this multi-tasking in iOS is all about saving the battery.
为什么 也许你会问
Why, you might ask?
屏幕上不能同时有四个app吗
Can't I have four apps on the screen at the same time?
这会需要很多处理器
Well that would be a lot of processor,
很多网络活动 很多电量消耗
a lot of network activity, a lot of battery drain.
因此 当应用在后台时
And so when an application is in the background
它没在运行 我们希望它消耗的电量最小
and it's not running, we want minimum battery drain going on,
如果要唤醒它
so if it's going to wake,
很多时候电量消耗都不是来自于你的app
and a lot of the battery drain is not necessarily what your app is doing,
而只是手机或iPad醒着的状态
it's just the fact that the phone or the iPad is awake, right?
它在运行 OS在运行
It's up and running, it's OS is running.
不过大多数时候 手机或iPad不用时都处于睡眠状态
So mostly the phone and iPad are sleeping when you're not using it.
你希望它保持这样
So you want it to stay that way.
如果你要把它唤醒
So if you are going to wake it up from sleep
开始消耗电量 你需要让尽量多的app
and start using battery, you want to get as many apps going
同时进行后台取回这些操作
with their background fetches and all at once.
而且 还有很多电量消耗很多的东西 例如无线电天线
Plus, there's a lot of very battery intensive things like the radio antennas, right?
wifi 电话功能 这些会消耗电量
The wi-fi and the cellular, those things use power.
因此 如果你要进行后台取回
So if you're going to do a background fetch,
这有可能会用到wifi 这会消耗电量
you're probably going to fire up the wi-fi, that's going to use power,
这时最好是让所有需要后台取回的人都一起取回了
we'd better get everybody who wants to do a background fetch doing it all at once.
这只是一个最小值
So this is just a minimum.
提到这个的原因在于
Now, the reason I'm mentioning this is
默认值是
because the default is
UIApplicationBackgroundFetchIntervalNever
也就是说从不进行后台取回
which means you'll never get background fetch,
因此 这个肯定需要调用
so you definitely need to call this.
注意 这还意味着
It also, notice, means
用户至少需要运行一次你的应用
you have to run your application at least once.
Your user has to run your application at least once,
如果你想要后台取回发生 这个需要被调用
and this gets called if you want background fetching to happen.
调用了这个后 系统知道你要做这个
Once you've called this, system knows you want to do that,
你到后台之后 然后是启动
you know, once you go to the background, then after that, the launch,
然后它就不只是唤醒你
then it will not only wake you up,
如果你退出或是崩溃
but if you were to exit or crash,
只要是进入了后台取回的世界 它还会重新开启你
it will fire you back up once it kind of gets you into the background fetch world.
用户不大喜欢应用在后台运行
Users might find that they don't like your application running
因为这会用掉很多资源
in the background because you use a lot of resources,
让你在后台取回 电量会被消耗
their battery gets drained when they let you fetch
或许你是一个很糟糕的后台公民
in the background, because you're a bad background citizen, maybe.
他们可以到设置里 把处于后台的你关闭掉
They can actually go into settings and turn you off when it comes to background.
有一个选项会说 不要让Photomania
Okay, there's actually a switch, it says "don't let Photo Mania
或Shutterbug在后台取回
or Shutterbug fetch in the background." Don't do it.
把这个设置为关闭 后台取回就做不到了
And if you set that off, then you won't be able to do it.
你可以通过这个属性看用户有没这样做
And you can find out if the user has done that, using this property
在UIApplication中 它叫BackgroundRefreshStatus
in UI application called background refresh status,
它会返回刷新状态
and it will return the refresh status.
状态有三种
It actually has three different states.
一个一切良好
One can be you're good to go,
二是用户关了你 三是受限
two can be the user turned you off, third can be restricted.
受限是什么 这在很多东西里面都有
What restricted means, and you're going to see this in various things.
例如在地图里面就有
You'll see this with the map stuff,
受限是说 你不能这样做 它被关了 但不是用户关的
restricted means you can't do it, it's off, but your user didn't turn it off,
他们也不能把它打开
and they can't turn it back on.
因为这在某方面受限了
Because they're restricted in some way.
为什么会这样呢
How would this happen?
例如家长控制
Parental controls, for example.
在家长控制中 某个程序很有可能不被允许
It's possible in parental controls to make it so this app is not allowed to run
在后台模式下运行
in background mode in parental controls.
再例如企业环境
Corporate environment.
一个企业有可能不允许程序运行在后台
A corporation might not want to allow a certain app to run in the background
因为取回的内容或是别的什么
because of what it fetches or whatever.
你需要检查所有这三种状态
So you've got to check all three of those states,
如果它处在受限状态 而不只是这个
and if it's in that restricted state, not just this thing,
如果它处在受限状态 你不要给用户说
but anything that's in a restricted state like that, you don't want to say to the user,
我想后台取回
"I want to do background fetches,
但你没有开启
but you haven't turned me on,"
因为这时他们根本没能力打开
because then they won't be able to go turn you on,
他们会说 什么 他们会很困惑
and they'll be like, "What?" Okay, they'll be confused, so
我只是想借这个机会讲讲这三种状态
I just want to make-- this is a good opportunity to talk about those three states.
一是开启 一是用户关闭
Okay, it's on, it got turned off by the user,
一是受限 意思是你无法开启它
and it's restricted, meaning it can't be turned on.
有问题
Go ahead. Question.
问题是 如果我想在后台做点取回外的别的什么呢
So the question is what if I want to do something in the background, but not a fetch?
答案是 你可以这样做
And the answer is, you can do that.
这个后台取回机制并没说你只能取回
This background fetch mechanism doesn't mean you can only fetch
你可以在网络上做别的事
on the network, you can do other things.
不过它叫作后台取回
But it's called background fetch and all that, I think,
苹果这样做是有原因的 他们可能想说
for a reason by Apple, is that they're kind of implying
这就是我们希望你用这个做的事
"this is kind of what we imagine you're doing with this,"
他们可能不希望你把程序唤醒
so they don't really want you to wake up and then just use a lot
使用很多资源做别的事
of resources somehow doing something else,
不过做别的事也是允许的
but you are allowed to do something else.
没有一条规则说
There's no law that says
后台取回被调用时
when the background fetch is called you couldn't make some
你不能进行任何数学运算 或是别的什么
mathematical calculation or something like that.
想想 有什么需要进行数学计算的
As you can imagine, what really would you be calculating mathematically?
从后台被唤醒后
Kind of, when you wake up in the background it's kind
你会希望检查正在发生什么
of like you want to check what's going on in the world.
我们会讲到如何检查诸如
And we're going to talk about checking things like
我在哪
"where am I in the world?"
这是另一码事
That's a different thing.
这方面有另一个机制 我会讲到这个
There's another mechanism for that, and we're going to talk about that.
有问题
Yeah. Question?
问题是 Facebook或是其它社交媒体app
So the question is, is this what, you know, Facebook or some social media app,
在有人发你消息时
that you know people are sending you messages,
是否就是用这个在说 有人给你发了消息
is this what it's using to say "someone sent you a message,"
那个小通知行 答案是 不是用的这个
Yeah, the little notification line, and the answer is no, this is not what it's doing.
那是另外一个机制 叫推送通知
There's another mechanism for that called push notifications,
很不幸 我们可能不会讲到这个
which we're probably not going to get to talk about, unfortunately.
这就是他们的做法
So that's how they're doing it.
有一种方式能让app的用户
There is a way to basically have a user of an app sign up
在服务器某处同意说
and say, with the server somewhere, saying "hey,
我愿意接受Facebook的推送通知
I'm willing to accept push notifications from Facebook,"
然后Facebook服务器就能发送通知
and then the Facebook server can send notifications,
一个很小的JSON数据包 给手机说
little tiny JSON packets, basically, to the phone saying
这里有条消息
"Oh, here's a message" or something like that,
消息可以是这个人获得了一条消息
and the message might be this guy's got a message.
你获得这些时 后台就有办法唤醒
When you get those, there's a way to get woken up in the background.
这是后台唤醒的另外一种机制
So it's a different mechanism for waking up in the background.
不过 如果你在Reddit或Facebook上
However, if you're doing something, let's say you're in Reddit or in Facebook,
你的页面放到上面
and you have your little page up,
上次你访问Facebook 你想要它更新
the last time you were in Facebook and you want that to update.
没人发送消息给你
No one is sending you a message, per se,
没有Facebook消息
like not a Facebook messaging thing, but it's just
只是人们在发自己的东西
like people are posting on their wall, you're watching
你在看发生了什么
or whatever is going on, and you want that to,
你到app切换器中时 希望看到发生了什么
when you go to the app switcher, you want to see kind of what's happening there.
不是实时的 不过是… 这就是这个很好用的地方
Not in real time, but kind of like...you know, that's what this would be great for.
在背景中唤醒 取回页面当前内容
So wake up in the background, fetch the current contents of the page,
更新 这时有人看app切换器
update it, now if someone looks in app switcher,
就能很快看到 哦 这里有新东西 他们可以点开看
they can quickly see "Oh, I've got new stuff there!" and they can go click and look.
明白了吗 这是不同类型的东西
You see? So it's different kinds of things,
发送消息后的通知
but sending a message and notification,
是推送通知 这是我们不打算讲的
that's push notifications, which we're not going to talk about.
问得很好
Good question though.
好 关于demo还有一点要讲明
Okay one other follow up from that demo is,
我用了一个小的demo工具
I kind of use a little demo ware in that,
在我们有机会进行后台取回时我用了它
when we got the background fetch, when we got a chance to do a background fetch,
我把它叫作startFLickrFetch
I called start FLickr fetch, okay,
为了让这里只有一行
just to make it a one-liner there,
我做的是很概念性的东西 也就是
that was almost a conceptual thing I was doing, just to kind
好 我们有机会取回 让我们取回吧
of say "Okay, we can have a chance to do a fetch, let's do it."
但实际上 调用startFLickrFetch并不好
But actually calling start FLickr fetch there would not be
甚至有可能无法工作
good, and probably would not work.
为什么呢
And why was that?
这是因为startFLickrFetch
That's because start FLickr fetch
开始了一个后台URLSession
starts a background session, URL session.
后台session是说 这是一个URLSession
Background session meaning it's the kind of URL session
如果URL返回 而你没在运行 你将有机会处理它
that if the URL comes back and you're not running, you get a chance to handle it.
那整个处理URL后台session 我们看过的
Right? That whole handle URL background session other one we looked at.
这些后台URLSession取回都是自由裁量的
Those kind of background session URL fetches are discretionary.
也就是说系统可以决定
Meaning that the system can determine, can decide,
如果你在后台 我不打算进行取回
if you're in the background, I'm not even going to do that fetch.
这些取回 你通常是在前台发送
So those are fetches that generally you issue them in the foreground,
它们可能在后台完成
they might complete in the background.
当你有机会取回时
When you get a chance to fetch.
因为这个fetch东西
Because of this fetch thing?
你希望就在那里进行取回 使用临时session
You want to do that fetch right there, using ephemeral session
就像我们在Shutterbug很多其它地方做的那样
like we did everywhere else in Shutterbug and stuff,
临时的常规session
ephemeral normal session.
而不是后台session
Not a background session.
这样就不是自由裁量的了 它会实际进行取回
That way, it won't be discretionary and it will actually do the fetch.
通过发送这个消息给你 系统在说
And since the system is saying, by sending you this message,
好 现在该你取回了
"Okay it's your turn to do a fetch,
我开启了所有的广播
I've fired up all the radios,
我准备好进行一些网络活动 开始做吧
I'm ready to do some network activity, go ahead and do it."
我上次课后发布的代码做了正确的事
So the code that I posted after lecture last time is doing the right thing,
它进行了实际取回 你可以去看看
it's doing actual fetch, so you can go take a look
iOS发送的后台取回消息
at the background fetch message that gets sent by iOS
你会看到我做的是实际的临时取回
and you'll see that I'm doing an actual ephemeral fetch,
我没调用startFLickrFetch
I'm not calling start FLickr fetch.
我只是想说清楚 为什么代码发生了变化
I just want to make it clear why that code was different there.
有问题
Question?
问得很好
Great. Great question.
问题是 有些事情在发生
Okay, so the question is something's happening and I'm
我在后台 我的UI需要更新
in the background, and my UI needs to get updated.
例如 URL返回 或是我得到机会进行后台取回
Like, a URL comes back or I get offered to do a background fetch,
我在做所有的事
I'm doing all these things,
这里难道不会有问题吗
and isn't there a problem there
毕竟我需要在主队列处理所有UI
because I need to do all my UI in the main queue?
这是一个很好的问题
That's the question, and that's a great question.
答案是 当你在后台运行时
But the answer is, when you're running in the background,
你并不在别的队列上
you're not on a different queue.
后台意味着 你不是用户正在看的app
That background just means that you are not the app that the people are looking at.
不过其它方面 它和在前台运行无异
But every otherwise, it's just like you're running in the foreground.
你可以绘制 你可以做任何事
You can draw, you can do everything.
你的主队列在运行
Your main queue is running.
当你有这样运行的机会时
When you get the opportunity to run like this,
运行的是你的主队列 你可以进行图像处理
it's your main queue that's running, so you can do graphics,
你可以绘图 做什么都行
you can do drawing, anything you want, right?
前台和后台之间的差别
So the difference between foreground
并不是主队列和非主队列之间的差别
and background is not main queue/some other queue,
而是app活动与非活动之间的差别
it's am I the active app? Am I not the active app?
这就是前台和后台之间的差别
That's the difference between foreground and background.
通常在后台时 你不会运行
Normally, when you're in the background, you don't get to run.
你的主队列没有任何周期 你的app没有任何周期
Your main queue gets no cycles, because none of your app gets any cycles,
一般都是如此
okay, normally,
不过偶尔 你会得到后台取回
but then occasionally you'll get the background fetch
或是URL会返回 或者你是一个location的东西
or URL will come back, or if you're a location thing,
就像我们今天要讲的
like I was saying we were talking about today,
你可以得到消息说 嘿 手机移动到了新位置
you can get messages that "Hey the phone has moved to a new location,"
你得到了一个我刚说的推送通知
um, you get a push notification that I was talking about earlier.
Facebook发了个消息给你
You know, Facebook sent you a message.
这些都会把你从后台中唤醒
Those things will wake you up in the background,
你会有一点时间来处理
and you can get a little time to process.
每次你得到机会在后台运行时
Any time you're given an opportunity to run in the background a little,
你都只有一点时间
you only get a little bit of time.
很好理解
Understandably.
你不能在那运行十分钟
You can't sit there and run for ten minutes.
这是为了让用户没用你的程序时
The whole point is to kind of keep you when you're not the app the user is using,
你不会用太多资源 免得浪费电量
we want to keep you not using a lot of resources so the battery doesn't drain.
问得很好 请讲
So good question. Yeah?
问题是 如果我获得了机会
So the question is, what if I get an opportunity to run
在后台运行这些机制
in the background here from one of these many mechanisms,
而且我确实要花十分钟
and I do start doing something that takes ten minutes.
这时会发生什么
What's going to happen?
答案是 系统会让你停止
And the answer is, the system is going to just stop you,
你的过程会停止
your process is going to stop,
你将无法完成
you're not going to get to finish,
而且这会导致很多糟糕事情发生
and that will create all kinds of bad things,
你的用户会说 怎么回事
your user will be like "what's going on?"
这对你也很糟糕 时间会超时
you know? And that's bad for you if things will timeout,
如果你在访问网络 各种糟糕事情会发生
if you're accessing the network, all kinds of bad things,
答案是 别那样做
so the answer is you don't want to do that, and the answer is,
系统不会让你这样
the system will not let you do it.
问得很好
Good question.
还有吗
Alright, anything else?
问得很好 这里的幻灯片很好
Great question, this is a great slide, because we basically got
这里我们基本是在考虑多任务处理
to talk about multi-tasking here.
下面 我们来继续Photomania演示demo
Alright, so let's talk about, continuing our Photo Mania demo here,
我说了 我要把它做成iPad程序
and like I said, I'm going to make it into an iPad app, actually I'm going
我要把它做成通用程序
to make it a universal app.
这将是一个很短的demo
Believe it or not, and this is going to be a fairly short demo.
我们这里创建了很多可再利用的部分
And we've kind of built so much reusable parts here
我们也有了很多知识
and so much knowledge that you have
我们现在可以很快用这些来做更复杂的事
that we can really quickly now make these apps do much more sophisticated things,
然后我还要演示一个你们没看过的东西
and then I'm going to demo a new thing that you've never seen before,
也就是如何创建弹窗segue
which is how to make a popover segue.
这是一类新的segue 几堂课前我们在课堂上讲过
This is a new kind of segue, we talked about it in lecture, a few lectures ago,
不过我没要求你们在作业中做过 也没进行过demo演示
but I never asked you to do it on homework, and I never demoed it,
现在就让我来demo演示一下
so I'm going to demo it here.
好 退出这个
Oh yes, okay, let's quit that.
让我们来运行Photomania
Alright, so, let's go run Photo Mania.
这就是我发布时的样子
This is exactly the way it was when I posted it.
看这里 这就是执行取回
So this is the posting, and you can see here, this is the perform fetch,
这里我做的是一个常规的临时URL取回
and you can see how I'm just doing a normal ephemeral URL
我们没有调用startFlickrFetch
fetch, I'm not calling start FLickr fetch here.
这个东西在跳动
And this guy is not...how, okay, I know how it is,
到时候我们会处理iTunes的
okay we'll deal with iTunes when we get there.
无论如何
Alright, so um, so anyway,
这就是我上周发布的东西
so this is exactly what I posted last week.
上周四
Last Thursday or whatever.
这个做了什么呢
So what did this do?
我们运行一下 回顾一下Photomania是干嘛的
Let's run this, just so we can remind ourselves what Photo Mania does,
它已经有半个星期久远了
it's been more than half a week, and there it is,
它在后台中进行取回
it just fetches in the background,
还有在启动时 取回了一系列最新的照片
and also when it launches, kind of a bunch of recent photos
从Flickr
from Flickr,
然后它给了一张表
then it basically makes a table
表中有很多拍照者
of all the photographers who took the photos,
这些都是拍照者 不是照片 而是拍照者
so these are all photographers, not photos, photographers.
不过我们希望能够点这些
But we'd love to be able to click on these
并看到某个拍照者的照片
and see the photos by that photographer, right?
但这里还不行 因为还没有segue
But we can't because we never put any segues in here,
我们什么都没做
we never did anything,
而且 我们的app在iPad上什么都做不了
and plus our app doesn't work at all on iPad,
让我们看看iPad故事板
in fact, let's go look at our iPad storyboard,
可以在这里看到 它只是这个空白屏幕
you can see it right here, it's just this big blank screen.
如果在iPad上运行 它将是一大块白屏
So if I ran this on the iPad, it would be a big, blank screen.
我们删掉这个
So let's get rid of that.
我想在这里创建我的iPad UI
Now, I want to build my iPad UI here,
做法我之前跟大家展示过
but I'm going to do it in a way that I showed you a little bit before,
这个很强大 我要复制粘贴自另一个app
but it's really powerful, which I'm just going to copy and paste it from another app,
记得吧 Shutterbug有一个iPad上很类似的UI
because Shutterbug, if you remember, had a UI on the iPad that's very similar
我们可以将它用到Photomania 来到Shutterbug
to what we want in Photo Mania, so I'm going to go over to Shutterbug.
这是最后编辑的Shutterbug
This is Shutterbug as we last left it.
看Shutterbug的iPad UI 这基本上就是我们要的了
And if you look at Shutterbug's iPad UI, this, it's kind of almost what we want.
Shutterbug展示的是照片列表
Shutterbug just shows the list of photos here,
如果我们能把拍照者列表插入到这中间
if we could just insert the list of photographers here in the middle,
我们几乎就得到了iPad上我们要的一切
we'd have pretty much what we want on the iPad,
下面我要复制所有这些
so I'm just going to copy all of this.
回到Photomania这里
Go back over here to Photo Mania,
我在我的iPad故事板中 粘贴
and I'm in my iPad storyboard here, and paste.
我需要全选这些
Oops, I guess maybe select all over here?
全选 复制 到这里 粘贴
Okay, select all, copy, over here, and paste.
放到了这里
So put it in here.
还是一样 我们需要找一下 哦 就在这里
As usual it's a little bit of a search party to find anything, oh, there it is!
这就是那个Shutterbug iPad UI
So here is that Shutterbug iPad UI.
我说了 我想要往其中插入
And like I said, basically I want to insert
一个照片列表
in between the list of photos
放到这里 让我能选拍照者
a thing here where I can choose the photographer.
也就是我刚在Photomania中展示的东西
The same thing, the thing I just showed you, that we were running in Photo Mania.
既然在Shutterbug中 就让我来抓取图像视图控制器吧
While I'm here in Shutterbug, let's grab the image view controller.
我们显然需要这个
We're going to need that obviously,
故事板需要用到它 把它放到这里
our storyboard uses that, so we'll put that over here.
复制进来
Copy that in.
这就是Shutterbug中我们需要的一切
And that's all we need from Shutterbug. So
这个故事板基本上就是我们要的了
this storyboard is pretty much exactly what we want,
只有少量东西需要修正
there's a couple of minor things we need to fix here.
一是 我们不想要这个照片列表
One thing is we don't want this list of photos
为我们的拆分视图的根视图控制器
to be the root view controller of our split view,
我们希望这里是拍照者
we want the photographer thing to be that.
在哪获得拍照者的表格呢
So where can we get our photographer's table?
这个我们也有 在iPhone的故事板中
Well, we actually have that too, that's here in our iPhone storyboard.
这就是我刚运行展示的
That's what I just ran and showed you, right?
这是列表 这张表
This is the list, this table
到检查器中看
if you inspect its identity
这是拍照者的Core Data表格视图控制器
is this photographer's core data table view controller.
这里展示的是拍照者的列表
So this is showing that list of photographers.
我们只需要复制这个
So let's just copy this.
把这个放到我们的… 哦 到哪去了
Put this in our...oops, and where did it go?
抱歉 有时很难找 在这里
Sorry. Sometimes hard to find all this, there it is.
注意到 它看起来很大
Notice that it looks really big.
这是因为我还没有segue到它 它还不知道
That's because I haven't segued to it yet, so it doesn't know
它会处在一个拆分视频的master中
that it's going to be in a master of a split view
并处在一个这样的导航控制器中
and be inside of a navigation controller like that.
让我们把那个根视图控制器放到这里
So let's go ahead and put that root view controller in there.
在哪
Where is it?
这是我们的导航控制器的根
Okay so here's the root of our navigation controller.
这个或许也叫作Shutterbug
This thing is also probably called Shutterbug,
把这个改成Photomania或是Photographers
let's change this to Photo Mania or maybe photographers,
因为出现在我们根视图控制器中的就是这个
because that's what's going to show up in our root view controller.
我要control拖动到拍照者那个
So I'm just going to control drag to the photographer's one,
并把这个重设为根视图控制器
and reset that to be the root view controller.
下面… 这里腾点空间出来
So now, let's get more space here.
现在我们的UI就更接近于我们想要的了
So now our API or our UI is a little more what we want.
我们这里有这个拍照者的东西 我们希望
We have this photographer's thing here, and now we want,
每次点击拍照者其中一行时
if each time we click on a photographer, one of these rows,
都会跳到一个照片列表
then we want to go to a list of photos.
让我们来做这个
Alright? So let's do that.
从这里control拖动到这里
I'm just going to control drag from here to here.
这处在导航控制器中 我要选push
And this is inside our navigation control, so I'm going to push.
现在就很接近于我们要的了
Now we're really getting close to what we want.
这是Shutterbug 不过这没问题
This is Shutterbug, but that's okay, that's going
这是标题 我们会重置标题
to be the title, we're going to reset that title anyway.
这个UI的问题是什么
And what is the problem with this UI?
这个UI几乎就是我们要的了 除了一点
This UI is actually exactly what we want except for one thing,
也就是 到检查器中看这个
which is that if we inspect this guy right here,
它是一个JustPostedFlickrPhotoCDTVC
it is a just posted Flickr photo CDTVC, right?
因为这是从Shutterbug复制来的
Because I copied it from Shutterbug,
Shutterbug显示的就是这个
and that's what Shutterbug shows, right?
刚发布的照片
The just posted photos.
而这里 我们希望它是PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
So really we want this to be something like photos by photographer CDTVC, right?
因为我们会点击这里的拍照者
Because we're going to click on a photographer here,
我们希望显示的是他拍的照片
and we want this to show the photos by that photographer.
大家都理解我说的话了吗
Does everybody understand why I'm saying that?
让我们把它设置为这个
So let's just set it to be that, and
我们将要创建这个视图控制器 让我们来做这个
we're going to have to create this view controller right here, so let's just do that.
文件 新文件 类
File, new file, the class,
这就是一个CoreDataTableViewController
it's going to be a core data table view controller.
我们将称其为PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
We're going to call it photos by photographer CDTVC,
我们需要确保这个等于这个
we've got to make sure this equals this, because
因为我刚把那个设置为了这里的类
I just set that to be the class in here.
把这个放到Photomania中
So let's put this -- I'll bring that, let's put this in Photo Mania.
有点怪 好 放到这里
Huh, that's kind of weird, okay...alright put in there.
好 这是我们的新PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
Alright. So here's our new photos by photographer core data table view controller.
我不想被这些垃圾弄得分心 删掉它们
I'm going to not have you distracted by all this junk, let's get rid of all that.
创建了新的视图控制器后再怎么做呢
When we create a new view controller, what do we do?
我们总需要想 这个东西的API是什么
We always kind of think of what is this thing's API?
它的公共接口是什么
What's its public interface?
我们来看PhotosByPhotographer的公共接口
So let's look at the public interface of photos by photographer,
也许你们有些人会想到
and probably some of you are imagining
这个很简单 它为非原子 强
that what this is, it's really simple, it's just going to be non-atomic strong.
我们需要传入我们要显示的照片的拍照者
We need to pass the photographer in that we want to show the photos of.
因此 我需要导入
So I'd better import,
导入Photographer 然后我可以有一个拍照者
import photographer, and then I can have a photographer.
这就是我们的公共模型 这就是我们的模型
Okay so this is basically our public model, this is our model
它是公共的 如果有人设置了这个拍照者
and it's public, so if someone sets this photographer,
我们需要显示这个拍照者的照片
we'd better show the photos by that photographer.
这是一张显示照片的表格
So this is a table that shows photos,
拍照者决定了显示哪些照片
photographer determines which photos we show.
在我们实现这个之前
Now before we go off and implement this,
我要先到拍照者的Core Data表格视图控制器
I'm actually going to go down to our photographer's core data table view controller.
这是显示拍照者列表的东西
This is the thing that shows the list of photographers.
这是我这一讲最开始展示的
That I started off this lecture showing you.
但愿你们记得上周三的代码
Hopefully you remember this code from last Wednesday,
它正在从拍照者中取回信息
you can see that it's doing a fetch to the photographer,
按名字显示 取回所有这些
showing them by name, it's fetching all of them right?
我要加入导航代码来导航
I'm going to put in the navigation code to navigate
从这个照片列表…
from this photos one right here, this is the list of photos,
抱歉 这是拍照者列表
sorry, list of photographers.
这里这个segue
This little segue right here.
给这个segue起个名字
So let's give that little segue a name,
叫它Show Photos by Photographer segue
we'll call it the show photos by photographer segue,
因为这就是它的作用
because that's what it does, right?
点击这里的拍照者 它就会显示照片
When we click on a photographer here, it's going to show the photos.
然后我要回到拍照者的Core Data表格视图控制器
And then let's go back to our photographer's core data table view controller
然后做导航
and let's do the navigation.
下面我要展示
Now, I'm going to show you something
你们在开发过程中可能要用的东西
that I think you should probably do for your development process,
也就是使用代码片段
which is to start use code snippets.
我们在一个周五辅导课上讲过
Now we talked about this in one of the Friday sections,
我不打算重复讲它
so I'm not going to go over it again,
不过这里我有一段我创建的代码片段
but I have a code snippet that I've created, for example, which is a kind
这是一段通用表格视图导航代码片段
of generic table view navigation code snippet.
开始键入它的名字 表格视图导航
So I start typing what I called it, table view navigation,
然后点回车 这就插入了进来
and I'm going to hit return, and it's going to put it in. So put this code in here
这是很通用的 它是做什么的呢
for me, and this is fairly generic okay? And what does it do?
它能为segue做准备
Well, it does prepare for segue
而且它还能做到didSelectRowAtIndexPath
and it also does did select row at index path.
这个能为一个表格视图工作
So this can work for a table view
也就是拆分视图的master
that is the master of a split view,
它还会为如下情况工作
and it will also work for something
也就是通过导航控制来segue
that it's just going to segue via navigation control or whatever.
它是如何工作的呢
So how does it work?
如果我们prepareForSegue
Well if we prepare for segue,
它会从sender获得索引路径
it just gets the index path from the sender,
这是一个UITableViewCell
which is a UI table view cell.
你们见过这个 没有什么新东西
You've already seen this code before, so it's nothing new.
然后它会调用这个准备
And then it calls this prepare up here, and we'll talk
马上我们会讲到这个
about what the prepare does in a second.
然后didSelectRowAtIndexPath
And then the did select row at index path, it does the trick
能够观察拆分视图的detail控制
where it's looking at the detail control of the split view,
如果是导航控制器
if it's a navigation controller
它会到里面找根视图控制器 然后做好准备
it looks inside for its root view controller, and then is preparing that.
大家都理解这两个方法是做什么的了吗
Everyone understand what these two methods do?
下面来看这个准备
Okay. So now we've got to look at this prepare,
因为这是实际做准备的东西
because this is the thing that's actually doing the prepare.
这是这个
So here's that.
这个的作用
And what this is going to do,
是把ManagedObject放到我们正在讨论的表格的行中
it's going to get the managed object in the row on the table that we're talking about,
它会检查我们segue到的视图控制器的类
okay, and then it's going to check the class of the view controller we're segueing to,
也许还会检查segue标识符
maybe it's going to check the segue identifiers as well, that's not going to be--
didSelectRowAtIndexPath并不是一个segue
you know, did select row at index path is not a segue,
因此这里并不适用
so it's not going to be applicable there,
不过我在这里检查 看是否有segue标识符
but I check here and see if there is a segue identifier,
如果没有 我就忽视这一部分
and if there's not, then I'd ignore this part.
然后我要准备那个视图控制器 用于被segue到
And then I'd prepare that view controller for being segued to
或者说 如果它是拆分控制器的detail
or if it's the detail of the split view controller.
这里 我们有拍照者segue到照片
So this case, we have photographers segueing
看看这是怎样的
to photos, so let's see what this looks like.
这里我们要找的NSManagedObject
Well, the NS managed object we have here that we're going
是一个拍照者
to be looking for is a photographer,
因此我要把这个换成Photographer
so I'm just going to replace this with photographer.
photographer
Photographer.
从取回结果控制器中 将对象获得到索引路径中
Just getting my object in index path out of my fetched results controller,
你们知道这是什么
you know what that is,
然后我们segue到的是哪类视图控制器呢
and then what kind of view controller are we segueing to?
我们将segue到这里的一个
Well, we're going to be segueing to one of these
我们刚创建的PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
photos by photographer core data view controllers that we just created.
这个的实现我们还没做
We haven't done the implementation of this yet,
不过我们知道要设置拍照者 它的公共API是什么
but we know what its public API is, to set the photographer,
同我们想的一样
which is exactly what we would want.
让我们导入这个
So let's go ahead and import that.
导入 PhotosByPhotographer
Import, m, import photos by photographer,
然后到下面这里
and then let's go down here and
检查这就是那个类 PhotosByPhotographer
check that that's the class, photos by photographer.
现在我们知道 这就是我们要的类
Okay, so now we know that that's the class that we want.
这里 这个segue标识符 我们可以在这里检验
Here, this segue identifier we can check that here,
记得吧 我把它设为了Show Photos by Photographer
and if you remember, I set it to be show photos by photographer, right?
大家都知道这是什么
That's, everyone know what that is, right?
也就是这里这个
That is this thing right here.
这个小segue
This little segue.
它的标识符是这个
Okay. Its identifier is this.
这需要匹配我们这里所做的事情
That's got to match what we're doing in here.
好 我们检验这个
Alright, so we're checking that, and again,
如果我们考虑didSelectRowAtIndexPath的情形
if we're doing the did select row at index path case
这里只是detail视图
where it's just the detail view,
那么 segue标识符就是nil 其长度将为nil
then the segue identifiers can be nil, so its length is going to be nil,
这里我用长度是为了
and so I use length there just in case to check
同等地检查空字符串和nil
for empty string and nil equally, either of them,
我用了非 如果没有segue标识符
and I'm doing not, so if there's no segue identifier,
那么只要我们要到PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
then as long as we're going to a photos by photographer CDTVC,
我们就知道我们要怎么做
then we know we're going to, what we're going to do.
有些人会认为 检查这个segue标识符
Now, some people would argue the checking this segue identifier
根本就不应该做
that you should almost never do that.
如果你要segue到PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
Because if you're segueing to photos by photographer CDTVC
从一个拍照者的CDTVC 你知道你在做什么
from a photographer's CDTVC, you know what you're doing,
你不需要一个segue标识符告诉你 你在做什么
you don't need a segue identifier to tell you what you're doing.
有些人会这样说
That's what some people would say.
我认为这种说法并不错
And I see that argument, it's not a bad argument,
我甚至赞同其观点 检查segue标识符
I even buy that argument that really you only when you segue identifiers
只应该用到有两个不同segue的情况下
if for some reason you had two different segues,
demo后面将有一个例子
and we'll talk a little bit later in this demo an example
你会碰到这种情况
of where you might actually have that.
你可以说 删掉这个
So one could argue just delete that, okay,
把这个完全删掉 不要检查
just get rid of that entirely, don't even check that.
这里我们知道 如果它是PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC
And here we know that this is a, if it's photos by photographer CDTVC,
pbpcdtvc =
photos by photographer CDTVC equals
(PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC *)vc
PhotosByPhotographerCDTVC by photographer CDTVC, star, VC,
我们有了这个
alright, so we have that.
下面我们将要准备视图控制器
So now we're going to prepare this view controller.
pbpcdtvc.photographer =
Photos by photographer dot photographer equals the
我们在行中选择的拍照者
photographer that was selected in our row.
我们会讲到这个
Uh, yeah, we'll talk about that.
问题是
So the question is,
我不需要将context传给这个新控制器吗
don't I have to pass the context to this new controller?
答案是需要 我在这行代码中这样做了
And the answer is yes, and I'm doing that in this line of code right here.
我们来看看PhotosByPhotographer
So let's go look at photos by photographer.
PhotosByPhotographer会获得这个拍照者
So photos by photographer, it's going to get this photographer.
我们在PhotosByPhotographer中需要做什么
What do we need to do in photos by photographer.
我们主要要做的
Well, really the main thing we need
是取回该拍照者拍摄的照片
to do is fetch the photos by that photographer.
我们来看看这个
So let's go ahead and look at that.
每次我设置拍照者 顺便说下 你们会注意到
Every time I set the photographer, and you're noticing, by the way,
每次设置公共模型时
any time you have a public model set, you almost always are going
你几乎总需要setter来更新你的视图
to use the setter to update your view when someone sets your model.
这是很显然的
That's kind of an obvious thing.
这里我还要将标题设置为拍照者的名字
One thing I might do here, by the way, is set my title to be the photographer's name.
这是一个很好的做法
That would be a good thing, right?
我是一个控制器 显示一系列该拍照者拍的照片
I'm a controller that's showing a bunch of photos by photographer,
我的标题显然应该是这个
so my title might want to be that.
不过这里我真正需要做的是 .
But the real thing I need to do here is
setupFetchedResultsController
set up my fetched results controller.
这是CDTVC需要做的主要事情
That's the main thing that CDTVCs need to do,
setupFetchedResultsController
is set up their fetched results controller,
然后这个会自动工作
and then they just kind of work automatically right?
为了节省时间 我提前准备好了 它是这样的
So to save some time, I have that ready to go here, this is what it looks like.
我会一行行讲 别担心
Let me, I'm going to go through every line of this, don't worry.
首先 回答你的问题 我如何得到context
So first is answering your question, how do I get my context?
我需要context 没有context就无法取回
I need a context, I can't fetch without a context.
答案是 我会问拍照者 你处在什么context中
And the answer is, I'm just going to ask the photographer what context it's in.
有人给了我一个拍照者
Someone gave me a photographer, and I'm going
我要弄清它来自什么context
to go find out what the context is from it.
这个拍照者来自某个数据库
That photographer came from some database,
我希望从相同数据库中获得照片
I want to get the photos in the same database.
我不需要单独传递context
So I don't need to pass the context separately,
它会和拍照者一同过来
it comes along with the photographer.
如果context为nil 要么拍照者为nil
If the context is nil, so either the photographer is nil,
要么拍照者不来自这个context 这是不可能的
or for some weird reason the photographer didn't come from a context, that's impossible,
大多数时候 拍照者为nil
but mostly this will be the photographer is nil,
这时 我会将FetchedResultsController设为nil
then I'm going to set my fetch controller results to nil, that
我的表格会为空
blanks out my table.
FetchedResultsController为nil 表格就会是空的
If you set your FetchedResultsController to nil, then your table's going to be blank.
这就是我要的 你给我一个拍照者
Which I want in this case, if someone gives me a photographer
没有context 或是给我nil拍照者
with no context, or gives me nil photographer.
不过其它情况下 我会为所有照片设置取回请求
But otherwise, I'm going to set up a fetch request for all the photos
我的谓词是 whoTook = 那个拍照者
where my predicate is who took equals that photographer.
大家应该懂这一行代码吧
Everyone understand that line of code, hopefully?
如果你开始了作业 你肯定能懂
If you started on your homework, then you understand it.
然后我将通过照片标题对照片进行排序
And then I'm going to show sort the photos by the photos title.
也就是通过照片的字典序来排序
So they're going to be in alphabetical order by the title of the photo.
这是照片上的一个属性 我们会用这个排序
So this is a property on photo, if you'll recall, and we're going to sort by that.
使用这种类似于finder中的排序
Use this kind of finder like sorting order, and then that's it.
我创建了这个self.fetchedResultsController
I just create this fetch, self dot fetch results controller,
它有这个我刚创建的请求
it's got the request right here that I just created,
这是我从拍照者得到的context
and the context, which I got from the photographer,
我没有做section那些 这里也没有缓存
and I'm not doing any sections, and there's no cache.
这里有问题吗
Any questions about that?
根据上次讲的 但愿大家都理解这个
Hopefully everyone understands that from last time.
这个PhotosByPhotographer表格还需要做什么
Now, what else does this photos by photographer table need to do?
没有太多东西了
Well, not much else, okay,
通过发送FetchedResultsController
by sending the fetch results controller,
它获得了结果 但它还需要显示这些结果
it's getting the results, but it has to display those results,
因此它还需要做cellForRowAtIndexPath
so it has to do cell for row at index path.
这是Core Data表格视图控制器能为你做的一件事
That's the one thing that core data table view controller cannot do for you,
因为它不知道对象的什么属性
because it doesn't know what attributes
你想显示在行中 我们需要这样做
of the object you want to show in the row, so we've got to do that.
它需要做的另外一件事是导航
The other thing it needs to do is navigation.
因为当我点击一张照片时
Because when I click on a photo, I want to have
我希望图像视图控制器显示它的图像
that image view controller show its image, right?
它需要做这两件事
So it needs to do those two things.
但我不打算把那些放到这个类中
But I'm not going to put those in this class.
为什么呢
Why am I not going to put these in the class?
因为这两件事是每个显示照片的
Because those two things every core data table view controller
Core Data表格视图控制器都想做的
that shows photos wants to do. Every single one of them.
因此 我要创建一个通用的
So I'm going to create a generic
照片Core Data表格视图控制器 它知道怎么做
photos core data table view controller that knows how to do that.
然后我打算让这个类继承它
Alright? And then I'm going to have this class inherit from it.
我需要强调这个
So I'm doing this to really emphasize because a couple
因为有些人还不擅于
of you, a few of you, are still struggling a little bit
使用面向对象的设计方式来创建控制器
with this concept of using object oriented design to build your controllers.
因此我这里重复了一下
Okay, so we're going to do it again right here.
我要创建一个新控制器
So I'm going to create a new controller.
这将是一个新的Core Data视图控制器
It's going to be a new core data view control,
名字叫PhotosCDTVC
it's going to be called photos, core data table view controller,
它的全部作用就是显示一些照片
and its job in life is to show a bunch of photos.
让我们这样做
So let's do that.
我们来看看它的公共API是怎样的 这里
Let's find out what its public API is, okay, here's its public API.
这个其实没有公共API 原因在于
This turns out to have no public API because all you need to do
它只需要关联fetchedResultsController
to make this thing work is hook up fetched results controller
到任何照片取回请求
to any photo fetch request.
这是一个Core Data视图控制器
This thing is a core data table view controller,
因此它有这个fetchedResultsController的东西
so it has this fetched results controller thing.
只要你将这个fetchedResultsController
As long as you set that fetch results controller
设置到任何照片取回请求 那么这个类就会
to any photo request, then the job of this class is going to be
显示它并让你从它开始进行导航
to display it and let you navigate from it as well.
通用
Generic.
对于任何照片都适用 你什么都不需要设置
Work for any photos, you don't even have to set anything except
除了fetchedResultsController
for the fetch results controller.
好 来看看这个的实现 很简单
Alright, so let's look at this guy's implementation, pretty straightforward here.
这些都不需要
Don't need any of this,
这里 我们只需要实现两个东西
so here we got to just implement those two things,
cellForRowAtIndexPath和导航
cellForRowAtIndexPath and navigation.
我们来看cellForRowAtIndexPath
So let's look at cellForRowAtIndexPath.
像这样 表格视图 cellForRowAtIndexPath
Looks like this, table view, cellForRowAtIndexPath,
当然 我们只需要获取单元格
and of course, we'll just get the cell.
这段代码 你们应该非常熟悉了
Okay this code should be very, very familiar to you.
到表格视图 dequeue…
Go to the table view, we dequeue, okay,
这个我叫作Photo Cell
I'm going to call this photo cell.
很有趣 这是一个通用类
Now it's interesting, this is a generic class,
它使用Photo Cell来再利用
and it's using photo cell as it's reuse thing,
我需要将这个信息放入到它的公共头文件
so I probably want to put that information into its public header file.
这里我说
So I'm probably here going to say
使用Photo Cell作为表格视图单元格再利用id
use photo cell as your table view cells reuse ID.
这样任何使用这个类的人
That way anyone who is using my class
就无需看它的实现
doesn't have to go look at its implementation,
他们可以从头文件获得这个信息
they can just get this information from the header file and do it.
确保我们做了这个
So let's make sure we do that.
回到这里 这是我们的PhotosByPhotographer单元格
Let's go back here, here's our photos by photographer cell.
我们看看它的单元格再利用标识符是什么
Let's see what its cells reuse identifier is,
答案是 哦 Flickr Photo Cell
and the answer is, oooh, Flickr photo cell.
因为这是从Shutterbug借用的 那里是Flickr
Because we stole this from Shutterbug, and Shutterbug is a Flickr thing,
我们这里是Core Data数据库
whereas we are a core database thing.
把Flickr这个词删掉
So I'm going to get rid of that word Flickr, and make sure
这就行了 Photo Cell
that this is what it's supposed to be, photo cell.
大家都理解了吗
Everyone understand that?
回到这里
So back to here.
有了这个Photo Cell 然后怎么做呢
So now I've got this photo cell, okay, what am I going to do with it?
我需要获得这个单元格中显示的照片
Well, I need to get the photo that I'm supposed to show in this cell.
这是Photo * 显然 我们需要导入Photo
So that's photo star and of course we need to import photo.
photo = [self.fetchedResultsController
Photo equals self dot fetch results controller,
objectAtIndexPath:indexPath]
object at index path, the index path.
也就是这个参数
This argument right here.
你们应该能够完全理解这个
This, hopefully, is completely you understand this.
然后我需要设置textLabel
Now, I just need to set the text label.
其文本设为照片的标题
I'm going to set it's text to be the photo's title,
然后设置detail 设为照片的副标题
and let's set the detail, the subtext, the subtitle thing, to the photo's subtitle.
然后返回单元格
And return the cell.
可见 写cellForRowAtIndexPath
So you can see that writing cell for row index path
在Core Data表格视图单元格中很简单
is pretty easy when it's a core data table view cell,
因为通常对于行中的对象 你可以得到一行代码
because usually the object in the row which you can get one line of code
里面有你要的 你只需要展示它
has what you want, you just display it.
下面 我们来讨论导航
Now, let's talk about the navigation.
我说了我有这个通用表格视图导航的东西
I told you I have this generic table view navigation thing,
这里我重新使用了它
I'm going to use it again right here.
同之前那个里面完全相同
So it's the exact same thing that I put in the other
我只需要确保 这个同我们这里相匹配
one, I just have to make sure this is appropriate to what we're doing here.
这是照片 ManagedObject还是Photo *photo
So this is photos, again, so the managed objects are going to be photo star photo, okay,
这样我就从行中得到了照片
so now I got the photo out of the row.
这个在导航中做了什么
What does this thing do in terms of navigation?
它会导航
Well, it will navigate
到一个图像视图控制器 并展示照片
to an image view controller and show the image.
让我们导入ImageViewController
Alright? So let's import image view controller,
因为这就是我们要导航到的
because that's what we're going to be navigating to.
到下面这里 isKindOfClass ImageViewController
Get down here, kind of class image view controller,
还是一样 这里我可以跳过segue这些
again I could probably skip the segue thing here,
因为如果我要导航到一个ImageViewController
because if I'm navigating to an image view controller
从这个照片的视图控制器
from this photos view controller,
我显然需要展示我的图像
I almost certainly want to show my image.
这就是我要做的
There's really nothing else I might want to do.
我来做这个
So we'll just do that.
ImageViewController *ivc =
So image view controller IVC equals
(ImageViewController *)vc
image view controller VC,
然后我们只需要设置ivc的imageURL
and we just need to set the IVC's image URL
等于一个NSURL
equal to an NSURL
使用photo.imageURL
with the photos image URL.
我这样做显然是因为
The reason I have to do this, of course,
图像URL无法存储在数据库中
is because you can't store an image URL in the database,
它只能以字符串形式存储
we stored it as a string,
这会将它转化为URL
so this converts it into a URL
因为图像视图控制器公共API用的是URL
because image view controller takes a URL as it's public API.
我这里还可以写 title等于照片标题
I could also do something here, title equals the photo's title.
因为图像视图控制器只有一个imageURL
Because really the image view controller, since it only has an image URL,
它没有足够信息
it doesn't have enough information
设置自身标题 同另一个一样 也就是拍照者
to set its own title, like the other one did, the photographer,
我们创建的这个的子类
this one-- this guy's subclass that we created,
这个无法做到 因此我们帮它设置标题
it knew how to do it, but this one really can't so we'll help it out and set its title.
大家都理解了吗
Everyone understand that?
现在我们有了这个很好的通用照片显示
So now we have this nice generic photos showing thing.
下面再让PhotosByPhotographer继承它
Let's go ahead and make our photos by photographer inherit from it, instead.
PhotosCDTVC PhotosCDTVC
Photos CDTVC, photos CDTVC.
它会继承cellForRowAtIndexPath和导航的能力
So now it just inherited the ability to do cellForRowAtIndexPath and navigation.
而且它仍然会自己去进行取回
Okay, and it still does the fetch itself.
它决定了显示什么照片
So it's the one determining what photos show up,
它的超类则将它们放到行中
it super classes the one, putting them in the rows.
都理解了这里是在做什么吗
Everyone understand what I'm doing there?
好 这很棒
Okay, so that's awesome.
大家都知道如何导航 都知道
Everybody kind of knows how to navigate, everyone knows how
如何加载自身 也许我们就只需要做这么多了
to load themselves up, and might be that's all we need to do?
看看还有没有别的什么
Let's see if I can remember anything else.
应该就这些了 看看能否工作
I think that's it. So let's go see if we're working.
我们在iPad上试试 在真正的iPad上试
Let's try this on the iPad, because we just built...whoops, let's do it on the real iPad.
我们刚创建了这个 让我们来试试
We just built this, so let's go ahead and do that and see
看有没有bug 能否正常工作
if we have any bugs, things not working.
或许我们忘记了什么 或许有些segue没设对
Maybe we didn't forget, we didn't set some of our segues right or something like that,
看看结果怎样
so we can see what's going on here.
这是Photomania
So here it's Photo Mania,
但愿它在从Flickr取回数据并放入到拍照者表格
so hopefully it's fetching from Flickr right now into this photographer table,
它这样做了 很好
and it is, that's very good.
这里 我们得到了拍照者
So here, we have photographers, right?
这就是Photomania的作用
That's what Photo Mania does.
Shutterbug取回的是照片 显示的是照片标题
Shutterbug fetched the photos and showed you the photos titles,
而Photomania取回照片 显示的则是拍照者
Photo Mania fetches the photos and then shows you the photographer.
我们可以看
And we can look and see, some
有些拍照者有三张照片 有些有九张
of our photographers have three photos, some nine,
让我们来选这个九张的
so let's pick this guy, he has nine.
再选这个拍了三张的
Let's pick this guy, he has three.
我们可以点选其中一张
And we can click on one of these.
但愿没什么… 这是里约热内卢 或许我们该选点别的
Again, hopefully nothing, this is Rio De Janeiro, maybe we'll pick somewhere else.
这里没有标题
No, there's no titles.
这个呢
Uh, how about this one?
也没有标题
Nah, there's no titles.
还是来看里约
Okay, we'll do Rio.
但愿里约没有什么糟糕的东西
Hopefully Rio is not going to do anything bad.
就点它吧
Here we go.
这是里约 很棒嘛
There's Rio. Oh, good! Not bad.
这就是我们的图像视图控制器 它工作得很好
Okay, so there's our image view controller, so this all worked great.
但愿在竖屏模式下也能正常工作
So hopefully it works here in portrait mode too
好像也能正常工作
and it does seem to be working there too.
好 这是这个
Okay, There we go. So that's that.
你们都了解了 它工作得很好
You guys all got that? It worked perfectly.
下面我们就可以进入到下一个内容了
So now we can quickly move on to the next thing we're going to show,
下面我们要展示的是…
which is we're going to show how to put a little--
这里用横屏模式
put it in landscape mode just to show here--
在这只鸭子的鼻子上面
so right above where this duck's nose is, okay,
我想放一个小按钮 叫URL 点击它时
I'm going to put a little button called URL, and when I click
它会弹窗 然后在弹窗中
on it, it's going to do a popover, and in that popover,
它会展示这里显示的URL
it's going to show me the URL that's showing here,
文本 也就是http://那些
the text of it, you know, http slash something.
这里主要是要给你们演示如何弹窗
Okay, so this is mostly to show you how to do popovers.
回头看看怎么做这个
So let's go back and see how we would do that.
其实很简单
This turns out to be quite straightforward.
这是我们的UI 我们希望做的是
So here we are, here's our UI, and what we want
在这里加一个小按钮 显示URL
to do is add a little button here that does URL.
我只需要把这个栏按钮项目拖到栏上这里
Okay. So we're going to drag this bar button item into the bar here,
我把它称作URL
and we're going to call it URL.
这将是一个栏按钮项目
Okay, so this is going to be a bar button item
点击它时会出现一个弹窗在这里
that when you click on it, it's going to bring up a popover here,
一个小的视图控制器会出现
a little view or view controller that's going
覆盖到其它东西之上
to appear, overlapping everything else.
怎么做到呢
So how do we do that?
答案是这样的
And the answer for that is
我们创建一个全新的视图控制器
that we create an entirely new view controller.
弹窗segue是常规segue
A popup, a popover segue is a normal segue.
segue到一个新的视图控制器
You segue to a new view controller.
我们将创建一个新视图控制器用于显示这里的URL
So we're going to create a new view controller that's going
to display the URL that's showing here in image view controller.
如何创建一个新视图控制器呢 你们都知道怎么做
Alright? So how do we create a new view controller, you all know how to do that.
到这里 到最上面
We go into here, we go up to the top,
将一个视图控制器拖出来
we grab a view controller and we drag it out.
这个控制器太大了
Now this view controller is quite big,
把它弄好看一些 这是我们的视图控制器
let's make it so we can see a little better. So here's our view controller.
这就是弹窗的视图控制器
So this is the view controller, it's going to pop over.
我们下面将通过control拖动创建一个segue
And we then just create a segue by control dragging,
按住control 然后拖动
so I'm holding down control, and dragging,
同其它segue一样 这将是一个弹窗segue
just like any other segue, and this is going to be a popover segue.
这是我们第一次选popover
So this is the first time we've ever done popover.
创建了弹窗segue之后 你就可以
So now once you create a popover segue, you can now kind
以任何你想要的方式创建这个视图控制器
of create this view controller how ever you want, it's a look, to pop over.
你需要设置它的大小
And one of the things you might want to set it its size.
毕竟弹窗不能这么大
Because if this is our popover size, that's not going
否则整个屏幕都被盖住就太糟糕了
to be good. It's going to cover our whole screen, that's going to be horrendous.
显示URL只需要很小的弹窗
So display URL, we only need it to be small.
一行就行了 不换行
And it's nice to have URL on one line so it's not wrapping
URL有很多斜杠
because URLs have all those slashes.
我们试试一个很宽的 让它能容纳在一行内
So let's try to make a really wide one that will hopefully fit in one line.
如何改变视图控制器的大小呢
So how do we change the size of a view controller?
一般的视图控制器
Because all our other view controllers have kind
都可以用这些模拟衡量来推测大小
of inferred their size using these simulated metrics right
这里看到推断大小了吗
here, you see this inferred size?
但弹窗控制器很特殊
But a pop up view, a popover's controller is
你可以改变它的大小
special in that you can change its size,
要想这样做 Xcode必须先知道它是弹窗视图
notice that you won't be able to do this until X code knows that this is a pop up view,
弹窗视图控制器 或者至少
popover view controller, or at least knows
这个视图控制器处在弹窗环境中
that this view controller is going to be in a popover context
因为这个弹窗segue
because of this segue right here, this popover segue.
这样做之后 进入视图控制器
Once you do that, if you go to your view controller
选择它的视图 self.view 你就可以到尺度这里
and select its view, self dot view, then you can go dimensions
编辑这些东西
and these will be editable.
宽和高
The width and height.
例如这里可以设为600像素宽 40像素高
So, for example, we could make this 600 wide, and maybe 40 pixels high.
或许看起来会不错
Which is probably a pretty good looking thing.
这就意味着 点击URL按钮时
So that means when we press this URL button it's going to pop
这个弹窗会出现 大小很合适
over and be something like that, that's pretty good size,
600是弹窗最大的允许值
600 is the widest they will allow you to make a popover.
如果指定数值大于600 它这里估计只会显示600
So I think if you specify more than 600, it's only going to show up 600.
高度可以任意设置
Alright, and you can make it any height you want,
不过显然 你不希望它太大 否则所有内容都会被覆盖
although obviously you wouldn't want it too big, cover up all content underneath.
弹窗会覆盖它下面的一切东西
It doesn't really make a-- a popover that would cover up everything, you would want
你也可以使用别的segue 例如modal segue
to use a different kind of segue, a modal segue in that case.
我们有了这个 这是一个普通的视图控制器
So we have this, and then this is just a normal view controller
otherwise, this little view controller thing.
我们需要创建一个视图控制器的子类 成为它的子类
So we need to create a subclass of view controller to be its subclass.
我们这样做
So let's do that.
这个视图控制器做什么呢
And what does this view controller do?
这是一个普通的UIViewController
Well, it's a normal UI view controller.
它的作用不过是显示URL
And it displays a URL,
我将称之为URLViewController
that's all it does, so I'm going to call it URL view controller,
这就是它的作用 显示URL
because that's what it does, displays the URL.
放到通常放的位置
We'll put it in the place we usually put it.
放到下面这里 放到这附近
Actually let's put it down here, eh, somewhere like here.
它的公共API是什么
What's its public API?
很简单 属性 非原子 强 NSURL url
Very simple, property, non-atomic strong, NSURL, URL.
这就是它要显示的URL
That's the URL it's going to display.
它的实现是什么
What's its implementation?
也很简单
Also really, really easy.
删掉这个
Let's get rid of this.
设置它的URL时 它会更新它的UI
It's going, when you set its URL, it's going to update its UI,
这不是表格视图控制器 我们需要更新UI
now this is not a table view controller, so we're going to have to write the update UI,
当视图确实发生加载
also when it's view did load happens,
也要更新它的UI 别忘了这部分
also wants to update its UI, don't forget this part.
当这是表格视图控制器时
Okay, when you have non-table view, table view controllers,
这个setURL可以在outlet设置之前调用
this set URL might be called before your outlets are set.
updateUI什么都不会做 因为你没有outlet
So update UI might do nothing because you have no outlets.
你要再做一次 viewDidLoad
So you want to do it again, view did load.
这个代价并不大 因此我打算这样做
This is very inexpensive to do, so I'm just going to do it,
也许是两次 如果有人要设置这个
possibly twice, if someone were to set this
而我的outlet已经设置 然后viewDidLoad发生
and my outlets were set, and view did load happened
这之后 它可能发生两次
after that, it might happen twice, but it's very inexpensive
但更新UI代价不大 我可以这样做
to update my UI, so I can do that.
我们需要写updateUI
So we need to write update UI.
要updateUI 我们需要一个UI
To update UI, we need a UI,
我们回到故事板 给这个一个UI
so let's go back to our storyboard and give this thing a UI.
对于这个UI 我只需要拖出一个文本视图
And what I'm going to do for this UI is just drag out a text view,
到下面这里
so I'm going to go down here,
找到文本视图 这里 之前我们用过
find a text view right here, we saw a text view from before,
文本视图放到这里
so I'm going to put the text view in here.
对齐一下
I'm going to line it up,
然后让它自动布局
let's go ahead and get its auto layout going,
我要重置 给出约束条件
so I'm going to reset to suggest the constraints,
我要检验它有没有做好的事情
I'm going to check to see if it did something good,
它显然做了
which, it definitely did.
它会紧跟超视图的大小 我很喜欢这样
You see that it's going to stick to the size of its super view, I like that.
我们再来检视文本视图 我不要这些代码
Let's inspect the text view, I don't want all this code,
这里我只要http://www.stanford.edu
I'm going to put like http slash, slash, www dot Stanford dot edu, okay, in there,
这看起来很糟 把它弄大一些
that looks terrible, let's make it a little bigger.
18点 这样就更好了
18 point, that looks better.
再让它居中 让它可选择
Let's make it be centered, let's make it be selectable
但不可编辑 用户可以选择这个
but not editable, so someone could select this and then copy
然后复制粘贴到浏览器
and paste it into their browser and look at it that way,
这很好 你显然希望它能这样
so that's good, we definitely like that.
这看起来很棒
So that looks pretty good.
这是样子很不错的URL
That's a pretty good looking view of URL,
然后再把这个和outlet关联起来
and so now let's go ahead and wire this up to an outlet.
注意到我这样做时
Notice that when I do that,
它会尝试UIViewController 为什么这样呢
it's trying to do UI view controller, why is that?
这是因为我们需要设置这个的id
That's because we need to set the identity of this thing
这是UIViewController
to be a URL view controller, right?
一个普通的视图控制器
This thought it was a general view controller,
这样做之后 它就理解了
as soon as I do that, you can see that now it understands
这是一个URL视图控制器
that this is a URL view controller.
下面我要拖动创建outlet到这个文本视图
So I'm going to go ahead and drag to create an outlet to that text view.
称其为urlTextView
I'll call it URL text view.
就是这个
There it is.
常规IBOutlet
Normal IB outlet.
下面我们采用代码全屏 像这样
Let's go ahead and go full screen on the code here, like that.
然后是updateUI 也就是
And now we can do our update UI, which is that,
将urlTextView设为URL
let's just have our URL text view's text be the URLs,
其路径
its path basically
URL中有个方法叫absoluteString
and there's a method in URL called absolute string,
这会返回URL的绝对路径
which will return the absolute path of that URL.
抱歉 self.url
Sorry, self dot URL.
绝对路径作为字符串 这就是我们要的 文本是字符串
The absolute path as a string, which is what we want, because text is a string.
我们可以做很多有趣的事
And we can do a lot more fun things,
带属性文本视图 设置字体 颜色等等
attribute a text view, you can set fonts, colors, whatever,
这里我们只打算写一个很简单的updateUI
but we're just going to do a very, very simple update UI.
现在有了这个URL视图控制器 我们将segue到它
So now we have this URL view controller, okay, that we're going to segue to.
这是一个segue 我们正在segue…
Right? This is a segue. We are segueing...
汗 我应该把doc放到别处
man, I should put my doc somewhere else.
我们正从这个视图控制器segue
We are segueing from this view controller,
这是一个图像视图控制器
which is an image view controller, right,
到这个 这是一个URL视图控制器
to this which is a URL view controller,
通过这里的这个segue
via this segue right here.
让我们给这个segue起个名字
So let's go ahead and give that segue a name.
叫作Show URL 这个名字不错
We'll call it show URL, that's probably a good name for it.
然后对它进行prepareForSegue
And let's do the prepare for segue for this.
这是我们要做的最后一件事
That's the last piece we have to do.
如何为这个segue做准备呢
So how are we going to prepare for this segue?
这是一个普通的segue
It's a normal segue.
这个图像视图控制器就是它发生的地方
This image view controller is where it happens, right?
UI就在这里 因此我们需要把prepareForSegue放到这里
That's where the UI is, so that's where we have to put the prepare for segue.
让我们这样做 把它放到下面这里
So we're going to do that. Let's put it right down here.
这里我要放一个#pragma mark - Navigation
So I'm going to put a nice pragma mark navigation,
然后我要写 (void)prepareForSegue
and I'm just going to do void prepare for segue.
这里 我只打算写
And so here, I'm just going to say
如果segue的目标视图控制器
if the segue's destination view controller
是URLViewController这类
is kind of class a URL view controller,
那么 我就将segue到它
then I'm going to segue to it.
没错 我还可以说 如果标识符等于Show URL
And yeah, I could also say if the identifier equals show URL,
不过为了更快一些 这里我们就不那样做了
but for speed here, we're just going to go ahead and not do that.
视图 控制器 类
View, controller, class.
这样我就有了URLViewController
Okay. So now I have the URL view controller.
urlvc = (URLViewController *)
URLVC equals URL view controller, uh,
segue.destinationViewController
the segue dot destination view controller.
我有了URLViewController
I've got the URL view controller,
我可以将这个URLViewController的URL
and I can just set the URL view controller's image, or sorry, URL
设为我的imageURL
to be my image URL.
我是一个图像视图控制器
I am an image view controller,
imageURL是我的模型
so image URL happens to be my model, right?
这样我就很好用它 我于是打算这样设
So I have it handy dandy, and I'm just going to set that.
现在我准备好了segue到这个
So now, I'm totally prepared to segue to this thing,
下面试一下这个 看它能否正常工作
so let's go ahead and give this a try and see if it works.
让我们选一张照片
Okay, so let's pick a photo here.
选一个更好的 回到里约热内卢
Let's pick a better one than that, let's pick, okay, let's go back to Rio De Janeiro.
好
Okay, there we go.
这个的URL是什么
So what is the URL for this?
会是某个Flickr URL
It's going to be something Flickr URL.
我们点URL 它展示的是这个
So we click on URL and it shows it to us.
Flickr的某个服务器群
Some farm, some server farm at Flickr.
很好
Excellent.
看起来很好 一切正常运行
Now, this looks like, oh, good, it's all working.
不过这里实际有个问题
But actually there's a problem here.
看这个
Watch this.
我打算再按一下URL按钮
I'm going to press the UR button again.
里约越来越模糊 甚至有些看不到了
Oh, the smog is building in Rio here, look at it, oh, it's getting so you can't even see.
这里发生了什么
What's happening there?
实际上 这个segue一次又一次发生
Actually, that segue is happening over and over,
弹窗越来越多
it's putting up more and more popovers.
这里实际有四五个弹窗 一层层覆盖
So there's actually four or five popovers over the top of each other,
于是图像越来越暗
that's why it's getting darker and darker,
这是因为每次有弹窗时 屏幕其它地方都会变暗
because the popover kind of darkens the rest of the screen when it puts it up.
我可以点别的地方
So if I click somewhere else,
这是取消弹窗的方式 所有弹窗会慢慢消失
which is how you dismiss a popover, it's slowly getting rid of them all,
直到最开始的那个
all the way back to the other one.
毫无疑问 这对于用户而言不是很好的UI
Needless to say, this is not a great UI, for the user,
我们不希望这样 如何避免这样呢
so we don't want this. Okay, why is this? How are we going to stop this?
我们准备这样做
Well, we're going to stop this when this
当有人点URL时 我们打算检查
segue, when someone clicks on URL, we are going to check to see
是否已经有弹窗了 如果有 我们将不再segue
if we already have a popover up, and if we do, we're not going to do that segue.
我来展示一下怎么做
So let me show you how to do that.
首先 我们要跟踪这个弹窗是否已经弹出
So first of all, we have to keep track of whether this popover is up.
做法是添加一个属性给我的图像视图控制器
So I'm going to do that by adding a property here to my image view controller.
设为弱属性
I'm going to make it weak.
除了outlet 我们很少使用弱属性
Here's one of the first times we've used a weak property outside of outlets,
这里用于UIPopoverController
but it's going to be UI popover controller,
urlPopoverController
URL popover controller,
设为弱的原因在于 我希望使用弱的性质
and the reason it's going to be weak is because I want to use the weakness
让弹窗控制器失去之后
so that when the popover controller is gone,
没有其它强指针指向它 于是我的指针会被设为nil
no one else will have a strong pointer to it, my pointer will get set to nil.
明白吗 现在我就总能知道
Get it? So now I'm always going to know whether
弹窗控制器是否在作用
that popover controller is up,
不过我需要初始设置它
but I've got to set it initially, though.
segue发生时 我需要设置这个到弹窗
I've got to set this thing to the popover when the segue happens.
我们来做一下 如何做到呢
So let's do that. And how do we do that?
我在幻灯片中说过 但你们可能不记得了
I said this in the slide, but you're probably like "what?"
现在我来讲下 也就是 这个segue
but now you'll see it, which is this segue,
如果是弹窗segue
if this is a popover segue,
它将是UIStoryboardSegue的子类
will be a subclass of UI storyboard
也就是UIStoryboardPopoverSegue
called UI storyboard popover segue.
popoverSegue = (UIStoryboardPopoverSegue *)segue
Popover segue equals UI popover storyboard popover segue, segue.
我可以只这样做
Now I could just do this,
不过我还可以更保险一些 我可以说
but I'm going to be a little safe and say
如果我的segue是UIStoryboardPopoverSegue这一类
if my segue is kind of class UI popover storyboard popover segue class,
那么我就要做所有这些
then I'll get it, then I'll do this.
我喜欢在做这样的事情之前先检查一下
I just don't like to do casts like that without, you know, checking first.
虽然这里很有可能是弹窗
Although if I got to here, it probably is going to be a popover, but,
不过我这里还是检查一下
you know, it should be a popover, but I'm going to check anyway.
然后我要将我的URL弹窗控制器设为
And now I'm just going to set my URL popover controller equal
这个弹窗segue的popoverController属性
to that popover segue's popover controller property.
看这个弹窗segue
If you look at popover segue, here's popover segue,
去UIStoryboardPopoverSegue的说明文档
I'm going to go to its documentation, okay, for UI storyboard popover,
你会看到
and you'll see
UIStoryboardPopoverSegue只有一项属性
that UI storyboard popover only has one property,
也就是popoverController
which is the popover controller.
我们这里是从segue得到了popoverController
So we're basically getting the popover controller from the segue.
很特殊
It's a special kind.
但愿大家都理解了这个
So it's a little-- hopefully you understand that-- everyone understand that?
有问题吗
Question? No?
这不是目标视图控制器 这是segue本身
Um, it's not, this is not the destination view controller, this is the segue itself.
这里我们没有说segue.destinationViewController
We're not saying segue dot destination view controller here.
问得很好
Okay, great question.
目标视图控制器 这个东西
Is the destination view controller, this thing,
是弹窗控制器吗
is that a popover controller?
答案是 不是
And the answer is, it is not.
它是一个URL视图控制器
It is a URL view controller.
弹窗控制器是另一个类
Popover view controller is another class,
不是控制那个弹窗的UIViewController
not a UI view controller, that controls that popover.
它不是
So it is not.
segue是一个StoryboardPopoverSegue
So the segue is a storyboard popover segue,
从这里面我们得到弹窗控制器
out of which we get the popover controller,
而目标视图控制器是一个URL视图控制器
and the destination view controller is a URL view controller.
大家都明白吗
Everyone got all that?
好 现在我们有一个指针
Alright, so now we have a pointer
指向这个URL弹窗控制器
to this URL popover controller,
离开屏幕时 它会自动被设为nil
and it's automatically going to get set to nil as soon as it goes off screen,
因为指向它的是弱指针
because it's weak. It's a weak pointer to it.
我们还有一件事需要做
There's only one other thing we need to do,
也就是如果那个在运行 就不要运行这个segue
which is not do this segue if that thing is up.
我在课上讲过这个
And I actually talked about this in the lecture, how we do this,
UIViewController中有一个方法叫
there's a method in UI view controller called
shouldPerformSegueWithIdentifier
should perform segue with identifier.
这是系统在问
And this is the system asking,
用户点击了导致segue的东西
someone clicked on something that's supposed to cause a segue.
我是否应该照做
Should I do it?
这里我们打算这样
And right here we're going to say
如果讨论中的segue的标识符
if the segue in question here, its identifier,
等于字符串Show URL
is equal to string show URL,
在故事板中它就叫这个
which is what it is in our storyboard,
这或许就是我们这里还要检查的原因
and this is the reason why maybe we want to check it here as well.
在demo模式中 我跳过那个
I skipped over that demo mode, but you know,
如果这里要检查 这里我们也应该检查
if we're going to check it here, we might want to check it up here as well.
无论如何 我们有了这个 这里我将要这样返回
But anyway, we've got this, I'm going to return, in this case,
如果这是URL 那么如果我有URL弹窗控制器 那么NO
so if it's a URL, then if I have URL popover controller, then no,
不要执行这个segue 因为已经有了一个弹窗
do not perform this segue, because there's already a popover up.
否则 我可以说YES 但我打算
Otherwise, I could just say yes, but actually I'm going
做点更巧妙的事 我要说
to do something a little trickier, I'm going to say
如果我有一个imageURL 那么YES 否则还是NO
if I have a image URL, then put it up, otherwise, also don't put it up.
看懂了吗
See what I did there?
有两个理由不直接进行URL segue
Two reasons not to put, do that URL segue.
一个原因是可能没有任何照片显示出来
If I don't have any photo showing, then that's one reason.
另一个原因是弹窗已经在那
Or if I have a popup already up.
否则 这很有趣 我有一个否则的情况
Else, now this is interesting, I have an else case here, which is
也就是super shouldPerform…
super should performs.
如果我没有阻止它 那么我就要
So if I am not preventing it, then I'm going
让超类UIViewController来决定是否进行这个segue
to let my super class UI view controller decide whether it should do this segue.
这几乎总会说YES 不过…
Which it's always going to say yes, pretty much, but...okay?
这里应该是返回
This should be return.
看看这能否修正所有问题
So let's see if that fixes all our problems
好 回到里约
Alright, so let's go back to Rio.
这是里约 点URL 很好 再点URL
Here we are, in Rio, let's click URL, excellent, URL again,
不断再点 它什么都没做
again, again, again, it's not doing it,
点其它地方 所有问题都修正了
click away, going to fix all our problems.
不过这里还有一个很琐细的问题 出于时间考虑
There is a subtle problem still here, which I'm not going
我不打算修正 毕竟我还要讲地图
to fix because of time, I need to get to the maps here,
来到竖屏模式 显示URL 看看如果
but if I go to portrait mode and show the URL, watch what happens
我点这里的拍照者来显示拍照者会怎样
if I click photographer over here to show those photographers.
哦 URL还在那里
Oh! The URL thing didn't go away.
我点其它地方 它本应该消失的
I thought if I clicked away from it, it's supposed to go away.
实际上 只要你在URL所在的栏上点击
And the answer is, if you click in the same bar that the URL thing is,
这个都不会消失
then it does allow you to click.
我在幻灯片中讲过 这叫passthroughViews
That's the thing in the slides that I talked about, called pass through views.
这整个栏都是passthroughViews的一部分
So this whole bar is part of the pass through views,
最糟糕的是 就算我点别的照片
and the real bad thing about this is, if I click on a different photo,
照片会变 但URL不会更新
it's showing me a different photo, but it's not updating the URL.
这太糟糕了
So this is really bad.
我会在后面发布的代码中修正这个
So I'm going to fix this in the code I post,
算了 就现在修正吧 更容易演示
actually let's just fix it right now, easier to show you.
我来做这个
I'm going to do this.
当有人将图像设置为新东西时
Whenever someone sets my image to something new.
在图像视图控制器中调用setImage
Call set image, I'm going to, in my image view controller,
我就会解除我拥有的任何弹窗控制器
I'm going to dismiss any popover controller that I have.
这样 如果有人打开右侧那个 然后点击
So that way if someone brings up that thing on the right and they click,
至少我会把URL弄走
at least I'll put away my URL.
我也可以用一些代码
I could actually have some code here
更新URL视图控制器 让它变化
that updated the URL view controller and made it change,
这不难 我只需要跟踪它
that wouldn't be that hard, I'd just keep track of it.
唯一的问题是 这就会让不一致
The only problem is then that would be inconsistent
出现在竖屏模式和这个模式之间
between this portrait mode and this mode,
因为这里 如果上面这里有URL
because here, when I'm clicking, if I had URL up here,
如果我点这里 URL会消失
if I click over here, it makes the URL go away.
因为这里这个同URL不在相同的栏中
Because over here is now no longer in the same bar as the URL.
我希望程序的行为相对一致
So I want my behavior to be at least somewhat consistent.
因此我打算在点击新东西时 URL消失
So I'll make it so that when I click on something new, it makes the URL go away.
好
Okay!
一个很好很大的demo 所有这些我都会发布
Nice big long demo, I will, of course, post all of this.
现在你就知道如何用弹窗控制器了 现在你们需要
Now you know how to do popover controllers, you should really have a good handle
很好地掌握Core Data表格视图控制器的使用
on using those core data table view controllers by now, I hope.
我还说过 我要做的是通用app 看这有多简单
Oh! I promised I would do universal app, look how easy this is.
我要这样转到iPhone 这是我的iPad
I'm going to do my iPhone, here's my iPad,
我复制这个 到iPhone里面
I'm going to take this, copy it, go over here to my iPhone,
删除这个 粘贴
get rid of this thing, paste.
回到iPad
Go back to iPad,
将我要的这个图像视图控制器复制粘贴过来
get this image view controller, which I need, go over here, paste it.
给它找个空间 粘贴
If I can find space for it. Paste.
好了 放到上面这里
Alright there it is, put it up here.
segue到它
Just need to make the segue to it.
control 拖动
Control, drag.
这是一个push segue
It's a push segue.
搞定
Boom. We're done.
现在iPhone就能工作了
Now iPhone will work.
想看它工作的可以下课来
You can come up after class if you want
就是这么简单
to see it working, but that's all there is.
很多时候 要同时在iPhone和iPad的UI上运行
So a lot of times when you're working on iPhone and iPad UIs
你只需要弄好一个 然后复制粘贴到另一个
you'll get one working and then you'll just copy and paste back to the other one.
或许有一些新特性
Get that one maybe working with some new feature,
复制粘贴合适的东西回来
copy and paste it in the appropriate things back to the other one.
明白吗 你可以在两者之间往复 很简单
See what I mean, you can kind of go back and forth between, pretty straightforward.
好 回到幻灯片
Okay! Back to the slides.
好了
Here we go.
第14讲 这里
Lecture 14, there it is.
好 今天地图肯定是讲不完了
Okay. So we're not going to get all the way through the maps stuff today,
这没关系 因为下堂课开始还有时间
which is fine, because I have a little bit of time at the beginning of the next lecture,
然后我还将在下一讲做一个map的演示demo
and then I'm going to be doing the map demo in the next lecture anyway,
这样大家记忆就会很鲜活
so it will be kind of fresh in your mind.
关于刚才的那个大demo 大家有问题吗
So any questions about all that big demo I just did?
听起来不错吗
All sounds good?
理解了吗
Understandable?
好
Okay. Alright.
MapKit 这里我要讲MapKit
Map kit. Basically I'm going to be talking about map kit here,
不过这之前 我要讲到另一个框架
but before I talk about map kit, I have to talk about another framework,
这是一个非UI框架
which is a non-UI framework,
这是MapKit框架的基础 叫作Core Location
which kind of underlies the map kit framework, called core location.
Core Location是一个框架 有一些对象在里面
So core location is a framework, has a bunch of objects in it,
关于当前设备处在于什么位置
that have to do with where is this device in the universe?
就GPS而言 也就是在地球上什么地方
Where on the planet, you know, where, in terms of GPS
或是根据其它因素决定 设备在哪
or other factors determining where it is, where is it?
在地球的什么地方
Where on earth.
它的基本对象是CLLocation
So, its basic object is a CL location
其属性包括坐标 包括纬度和经度 然后还有高度
that it concludes a coordinate which is, you know, latitude and longitude, altitude.
水平/竖直精度
Horizontal and vertical accuracy,
我们会谈到这个的重要性 时间戳 速度
we'll talk about why that's important, time stamps, speed,
路线等等这些
course, things like that.
这就是CLLocation对象
That's the CL location object.
这个对象有一个很重要的属性 叫坐标(coordinate)
This object has this very important property called coordinate,
这是一个C struct
and that is a C-struct,
CLLocationCoordinate2D
CL location coordinate 2D,
其中是CLLocationDegrees
and inside is just CL location degrees,
这是一个双精度纬度值 另外一个是经度值
which is essentially a double, which is latitude, and another one which is longitude.
然后高度是以米计的
And then the altitude is in meters.
这就是Core Location中的基本对象
Okay, so this is the basic object in core location.
问题是 如何…
So the question is how do...oh!
抱歉 让我讲讲精度 它很重要
sorry, let me talk about accuracy, very important.
当你获得一个位置时
So when you get a location,
这个位置可能会具有变化精度
you got it in a certain way that might have varying accuracy.
如果位置是从GPS获得的 那就会非常准确
If you got that location from GPS, it could be very accurate.
如果是通过当地电话塔得到 那就可能非常不准
If you got it by looking at local cell towers, it might be pretty inaccurate.
可能会差一英里远
Right? It could be a mile off, actually.
两者之间还有一些方式
If you got it that way. And there's ways in between.
在斯坦福校园 你可以通过使用wifi得到
On Stanford campus, you can actually get it by using wi-fi.
它会寻找周围的wifi 以此告诉你你在哪里
It can look around, see what wi-fi things are near you and tell by that where you are.
听起来有些恐怖吧 它知道你在哪
Kind of scary, huh? So it knows where you are.
哪怕是在室内 这个也能奏效
And that works even if you're indoors or whatever, so.
现在 这只适用于公共wifi节点这些
Now, it only works for public wi-fi nodes, et cetera,
不过在斯坦福 这些wifi节点都众所周知
but at Stanford, these wi-fi nodes are all well-known,
因此 它知道你在哪
so it knows where you are.
指定这个精度可以使用
And you specify this accuracy using one
这些kCLLocationAccuracy常数
of this KCL location accuracy constants,
有一个叫BestForNavigation
and so there's best for navigation,
如果你想要这个精度
if you want that kind of accuracy, that's going
它会消耗电量 因为它会持续通信GPS
to use your battery because it's going to be constantly doing GPS.
这只在电话插入到电源时适用
So that would be only if your phone was plugged in,
例如在车上 插入到点烟器或是别的什么里
like you're in your car, and it's plugged into the cigarette lighter or whatever,
现在车上应该还有USB端口 无论如何
or I guess they have USB ports nowadays in cars, but anyway,
你需要有电源
you would want power there.
然后是Best 这也是GPS 不过不那么耗电
Then there's best, which is also GPS, but not quite as power hungry,
然后一直往下 使用wifi
and then all the way down using wi-fi
这些东西的精度越来越弱
and these other things to less and less accuracy,
无论位置如何获得 它都会汇报使用的精度是多少
but how ever the location was found, it will also report to you what accuracy it used.
无论是水平方向 还是竖直方向的高度
Both in terms of horizontally and then altitude wise, vertically.
理解精度关系到电量
Understand that accuracy means power.
要求越精准 所耗电量也会越大
The more accuracy you ask for, the more power you're going to use.
请选择程序能工作的最小精度
So ask for the least accuracy your application can deal
这样就能避免用电过度
with so that you use as little power as possible.
这一点很重要
Very important point.
这里还有一些属性 我不打算讲
Okay, some other properties there, I'm not really going
这里我只提供幻灯片
to talk about them, you have the slides for them.
很明显的东西 速度
Obvious things, speed
通过看所有点如何随时间运动来计算
is calculated by seeing all the points that you're moving through time,
速度可以计算 诸如此类
and it can calculate your speed, things like that.
那如何获得这些Core Location对象呢
So how do you get one of these core location guys?
我要获得一个Core Location对象 它会告诉我我在哪
I want to get a core location object, it says where I am right now.
答案是 使用这个类 名为CLLocationManager
And the answer is, you use this class called CL location manager.
你实例化一个CLLocationManager
So you instantiate a core location manager, CLLocationManager
然后你进行一些设置
and you're going to set some things up about it,
然后你要它开始告诉你 你在哪里
and then you're going to tell it to start telling you where you are,
它有一个委托
and it's got a delegate,
它会告诉委托 你在哪里
and it's going to start telling that delegate where you are.
这就是它的工作方式
So that's basically how it works.
在调试器中 你可以模拟你的位置
Now, you can simulate where you are, by the way, in the debugger.
使用调试栏的这个下拉菜单
With this little thing down by the debug bar,
这里有一些位置 你可以模拟
place where the pause and all that, you can just simulate where you are,
你还可以往其中添加地点
you can even add places that you are,
你可以在这里有很多位置
if you want to like have a whole series of locations
用于检查你的应用程序是否能够正常工作
that you want to check running through to see if your application is working.
这是一个模拟位置的很酷的方式
So this is a really cool way to simulate being somewhere.
好 CLLocationManager
Alright, so CL location manager,
如何使用这个来得到我们的位置呢
how do we use this thing to get our location?
你创建它 然后检查你的硬件
You create it, you check to see what hardware you have,
因为不同的设备iPhone4 iPhone5 iPad
because every different device, iPhone 4, iPhone 5, iPads,
都有不同的硬件 用于确定位置
have different hardware in them for figuring out where they are,
因此 你要检查硬件
and so you're going to check to see what's available.
然后 你要设定这个委托
Then you're going to add, set this delegate
为你想要的任意对象
to be any object you want, and then you're going
然后你要配置 你要怎样的更新 精度这些
to configure it for what kind of location updates you want, accuracy, things like that,
然后让它运行
and then you're going to start it running.
它这就会向你汇报 你在哪里
And it's going to start reporting to you where you are.
那么 有哪些位置监控可用呢
So what kinds of location monitoring are available?
有基于精度的汇报
There is accuracy based reporting.
你指定一个精度 它在精度范围内告诉你你在哪
So you specify an accuracy and it will tell you to that accuracy where you are.
你还可以得到更新
There's updates that you can get
它只在重大位置变化时才会发消息给你
where it will send you a message only when a significant change in position has happened.
假想这里使用的是电话塔这之类
Imagine maybe it's using cell towers or something there,
也有可能使用的是wifi
or if wi-fi is fired up for other reasons, it might be able to be using wi-fi, right?
估计不会是GPS
But it's probably not going to use GPS.
只在重大变化发生时告诉你
Only when significant changes occur.
然后还有基于区域的更新
You also have region based updates.
在干洗店周围设一个圈
Put a little circle around the dry cleaners,
你经过时 它会告诉你 你正在干洗店附近
when you walk by or drive by, it will tell you, "Oh, you're by the dry cleaner."
这是区域
So that's region.
你可以设定一个小的圆形或信标区域 我会谈到这些
So you can set up a little region, circular regions, beacons, we'll talk about those.
然后你还可以监控你的前进方向
And then you can also monitor your heading.
我正朝哪个方向走
So which way am I walking?
这可能会用到罗盘 可能会用到GPS
Okay, so that might be using a compass, might be using GPS,
取决于设备有什么
just depends on what the device has.
我说了 你首先应该检查能力
So the first thing I said was, you've got to check the capabilities.
这里有一些方法 出于时间考虑 我不会都讲
So here's a whole bunch of methods, I'm not going to go through them for time reasons,
不过你需要检查这些
but you need to check these.
例如 用户可能会对你关闭定位服务
Because, for example, the user might have turned off location services for you.
你需要知道 你需要作出应对
So you've got to know, you've got to deal with that,
你可以要他们重新打开
either ask them to turn it back on, okay,
这里也可能有受限的情况
there's this restricted thing for this too.
你也可能在app中做些别的什么
Or whatever you want to do, or do some different thing in your app,
你可能处在没有这些位置更新的设备
if you work with all those location updates or whatever,
程序所在的设备甚至有可能没有你想要的硬件
you might be on a device that doesn't have the hardware you need to do what you want,
最开始创建LocationManager时 你需要检查所有这些
so you need to all check all this when you first create your location manager.
获得信息后 你可以问LocationManager
So then getting it, you can ask a location manager,
我现在在哪 但我们从不这样做 我们会用委托
"where am I right now?" Kind of poll it? We never do that. We use this delegate thing.
下面我来讲讲委托这些
So let's talk about how the delegate thing works.
首先 你要指定想要的精度
First, you specify the accuracy.
这是一个LocationManager属性 desiredAccuracy
This is location manager property, desired accuracy,
之前我讲了精度
I showed you the accuracies before.
指定这个
Specify that.
你还要指定一个距离过滤器(distanceFilter)
And also you can specify a distance filter, in other words,
在用户移动这么远之前 不要告诉我
until the user moves at least this far, don't even tell me.
如果用户没移动一百米或是一千米 不要跟我讲
So if they don't go at least 100 meters, or a kilometer, don't tell me about it,
这也能省电
so that saves battery too.
这些设备中的GPS芯片 特别是最新的那些 都非常棒
The chip, the GPS chip in these devices, especially newer ones, really awesome.
这里指定的很多东西可以被加载到芯片中
A lot of this stuff that you specify here gets loaded into the chip,
然后芯片会亲自计算你在哪
and the chip by itself is calculating where you are
你是否移动了足够远 等等
and whether you went far enough and all that stuff,
然后重新唤醒手机
and then waking the phone back up.
整个手机在睡眠 但GPS却在监视
The whole phone can sleep and the GPS is still watching,
如果你能让这些最好地协作
and so if you can tune these to be as minimal as possible,
设备的电量会节省很多
you will save a ton of battery in the device, because only
因为只有GPS芯片在监控
that GPS chip will be watching, you know, what's going on.
然后更新的获取需要调用方法
Okay so then you start getting the updates
startUpdatingLocation
by just calling start updating location,
你的委托会基于你指定的精度和距离过滤器
and your delegate will start getting sent messages based on the accuracy and the filter
开始得到消息
that you specify for distance.
这个委托方法是怎样的呢
What does that delegate method look like?
locationManager didUpdateLocation是其中之一
Location manager did update to location from location, is one of the ones.
其实还有其它一些
There's actually some other ones that you could get sent,
你可以检查一下这个的说明文档
so you want to check the documentation on this one,
不过这个最基本 它说 好
but this is the basic one, where it's saying "Okay,
我得到了一个新位置 在这里
I got a new location, here it is," that location
这个位置显然有精度 时间戳等所有这些
of course will have accuracy and time stamp, all these other things in there,
它会给你一个位置 便于你来使用
and it just gives you the fun location just for your own convenience,
如果你只想看差异 你就不需要跟踪
so you don't have to keep it if you just want to see the difference.
这是这个 LocationManager在我看来非常简单
So that's it. It's quite simple, actually to use this location manager.
不过要在一小时内耗完用户的电量也很容易
It's also quite simple to drain the user's battery in about an hour,
务必小心 务必知道自己在做什么
okay, so be careful and know what you're doing here.
跟踪前进方向也有一个类似的API
There's a similar API for heading, for tracking the heading.
委托可以汇报错误
The delegate can report errors, and this is one case.
很多时候 我在demo中都对NSError说nil
A lot of times you see me in my demos, I just say nil for the NS error,
我忽略了错误
and I ignore errors,
有时 这样做没问题 例如Flickr取回时
and sometimes that's okay, like if I'm doing a Flickr fetch
失败了也没关系 因为我知道
and if it fails, I just don't care because I know I'm going
二十分钟内我还会再次取回
to be doing another fetch in 20 minutes,
于是我就让它失败 其实哪怕那里
so I'll just let it fail, although even there,
我也应该检查 如果它持续失败
I probably want to check it, and if it keeps failing over and over,
或许我就应该让用户参与进来
then I need to maybe get the user involved.
不过这里 你需要检查错误
But here, you really want to check the errors.
还是出于时间考虑 我只能
Okay, and again for time reasons, I don't have time to go
细到说这些错误有可能出现
through the details more than just that these errors can occur,
不过面对特定错误 你需要做特定的事情
but there are certain things you need to do in certain errors
这样才能写出优秀的Core Location获取app
if you really want to be a good core location getting app.
后台 这些位置更新能否在后台获得
Um, background, can you get these location updates in the background?
我保证我会讲这个 而且还有一张幻灯片
Okay, I promised I was going to talk about this, and I even have a slide about it.
答案是 能
And the answer is, you can.
你甚至可以让app
You can even sign up to be the kind of app
一般只在后台运行位置管理器
that gets the location manager will just run in the background normally.
这是相同位置 记得吗
It's the same place, remember when we went
我在讲后台取回时讲过
and did the background fetches, we had to go
有项目设定可以选
to our project settings, and we clicked that switch?
位置也有一个开关
There's another switch there that's just location,
开启后 你就会得到这个
and when you do that, you'll start getting this.
不过这只适用于健身app
But that's really for apps like, you know, a fitness app
你把手机放口袋里跑步
where you're going off to do a mile run and your phone is
手机在后台记录你的进度
in the pocket and it's tracking your progress,
你把手机调好
and you've tuned it to, you know,
让它进行联合 记录轨迹 并向你汇报
coalesce things and to keep track of it and report it to you.
如果你做健身app 你可能会很快耗光电量
You know, when you do a fitness app, you can really drain the battery fast.
顺便说下 期末项目不要做健身app
So if you're doing a fitness app, by the way, which don't do
that for your final project, but,
不过如果你以后真的要做健身app
if you're doing a fitness app, for the real, for real,
那么你就需要很清楚自己在做什么
then you really got to know what you're doing. So really investigate that
否则电量会受不了 不过你还是可以做很多很酷的事
because you really want to be low power, but you can still do lots of cool things
这在跟踪用户跑步时是可以做到的
when it comes to tracking where the user's running.
无论如何 像这样在后台运行
However, running in the background like that,
由于会用掉很多电量
since it uses a lot of battery, is generally only for very,
只用于极少量的app
very, very, very small number of apps.
不过有两种方式可以获得关于你在哪的后台通知
But there are two ways to get background notifications about where you are, okay,
且只消耗很少电量
that are very low power,
但它们都非常粗略
and they're a little coarser granularity, they're not going
它们不能准确知道你在什么地方
to be running down the trail telling me exactly where I went on the trail,
不过它们能大致告诉你 你在哪
but they are telling you kind of where you are
这对很多app都很有用
and are really useful for a lot of apps.
我来讲讲这两种方式 你可以得到通知
So let's talk about the two ways that you can get notified
后台和前台都行
in the background and in the foreground.
只要能在后台得到通知
If you can get notified in the background, then you're going
你当然也会自动在前台得到通知
to get notified in the foreground automatically.
这就是一种后台和前台都得到通知的方式
Here's a way that background and foreground, you can get notified.
第一种方法是显著位置变化监控
The first one is called significant location change monitoring,
你只是获得一个CLLocationManager
and you just get a CL location manager
然后你说startMonitoringSignificantLocationChanges
and you can say start monitoring significant location changes,
然后 当用户移动了显著距离时
and then when the user moves a significant amount of distance,
你就能通过委托得到通知
you will get notified via your delegate.
就这么简单
It's as simple as that.
哪怕是在后台 这也能工作
And this works even if you're in the background.
哪怕在应用没有运行的时候
Even if your application is not running.
应用也会得到启动 告诉用户移动到了新地方
You will get launched to be told that the person moved to a new space.
这是一个很妙的API 非常节能高效
This is an awesome API, okay, very power efficient
因为它知道如何管理跟踪位置
because it knows how to manage tracking where you are
以一种高效的方式 同时超级有用
in an efficient way and still super useful for you.
它唯一的缺点就是要求显著距离变化
The only downside of it is significant distance. You have to be going significant distance.
有问题
Question?
问题是 我们对显著的定义有没有控制
The question is do we have any control of the definition of significant,
答案是没有
the answer is no.
当你的程序没有运行
So yeah, so when you get launched in the background,
然后在后台被启动时
if you get launched, like you're not running,
application didFinishLaunchingWithOptions会被发送
you'll get your application did finish launching with options thing will be sent,
不过这里会有一个字典
but there will be a dictionary there, and one of the things
字典中会有UIApplicationLaunchOptionsLocationKey
in the dictionary will be UI application launch options location key,
如果里面有这个键 这意味着你被启动了
and if that key is in there, that means you got launched
因为有显著变化发生 你就是这样知道 哦
because a significant change happened, so that's how you know, "Oh,
因此我被启动了
that's why I got launched," okay?
因为这个键
Because of that key.
另外一种在后台定位的方式是基于区域的监控 非常类似
Another way to find out in the background is region based monitoring, very similar,
只是这里 你指定的是一个圆形区域
except for here you actually specify either a circular region
或是一个信标区域
or you can also specify a beacon.
等下我会讲到这个
And I'll talk about that in a second.
你可以指定地球上的一个圆形区域
So you specify circular region on the planet, you know,
一个坐标 以及周围的半径
coordinate, and then a radius around it,
只要用户进入这个区域 你就会得到通知
and if the user goes into that region, you'll get notified,
你的委托会发送消息 有必要时你还会被启动
your delegate will send a message, or you'll get launched if necessary,
这样你就能知道
and you'll find out.
没错 这个能有多少是受限制的
Now, yes, there's a limit to how many of these you can have,
具体多少我不知道 可能是40个左右吧 你的app
I don't know what it is, 40 or something like that, your app,
不过 这个也非常高效
and but this is also incredibly efficient.
这个也作用于低能耗高效率的基础上
So this is happening at a very lower, power-efficient level as well.
圆形区域很明显 你创建一个CLCircularRegion
The circular region is obvious to create, you just create a CL circular region.
信标更有趣一些
The beacon is a little more interesting,
我没有太多时间讲信标
and I don't really have time to talk about the beacon,
信标针对的不是地球上的位置 而是另一个设备
but a beacon is basically not a place on earth, but it's another device.
你可以写个程序 让设备成为信标
It's possible to write an application that essentially is a beacon,
它会一直广播出去
and it's broadcasting all the time,
如果你的app离它很近 你会被唤醒 设备会告诉你
and if your app comes close to it, you'll get woken up and told
你进入到了广播设备附近的区域内
that you went into the region of that broadcasting device.
这是iOS7的新特性 棒极了
This is new for iOS 7, incredible.
我很想看看 人们会用这个特性做些什么
Okay, I'm really interested to see what people come up with this technology.
成为一个信标… 这里 顺便说下
Becoming a beacon is, here, by the way,
是一个委托方法 didEnterRegion
is the delegate method you get, did enter region
还有didExitRegion 你会被启动
and did exit region, and you'll get launched.
信标 成为一个… 抱歉 这里我有点快进了…
The beacon is becoming a-- sorry, I'm fast forwarding here--
区域是按名称跟踪的 这是因为
uh, yeah, regions are tracked by name, that's because they have
它们在你没有启动时需要退出
to exist when you're not launching,
还有最大监控距离
there are maximum monitoring distances.
好 信标
Uh, okay so beacons.
要成为一个信标 你需要使用Core Bluetooth库
To become a beacon, you need to use the core bluetooth library,
这不属于Core Location
it's not part of CL core location library.
你可以查阅CBPeripheralManager
So you want to look up CB, core bluetooth, peripheral manager,
看看如何成为一个信标
and find out if you want to become a beacon.
你想成为信标 而不是探测信标
Like you want to be the beacon, not detect a beacon,
探测信标用这个
but if you want to detect a beacon, you use this.
你创建一个信标区域 CLBeaconRegion
You create a region, which is a beacon region, CL beacon region,
你指定信标的特殊标识符
and you specify its special identifier that identifies
靠近时它就会告诉你
that beacon, and it just tells you when you get close,
它甚至可以告诉你 你离信标有多近
it will even tell you how close you are to the beacon.
你离它是远是近 还是正在它上面
Are you near it, or far, or right on top of it.
这非常酷
So it's pretty darn cool.
这就是区域 区域监控
So that's regions. Region monitoring.
区域和显著变化都能在后台通知你
So both region and significant changes will notify you in the background.
MapKit留给下一讲吧
So map kit, I'm going to talk about next time.
它是一个用户界面
And it is basically a user interface
显示这些美丽的地图
for putting these beautiful maps,
不过显然 我们需要这些Core Location的东西
but obviously we needed that core location stuff to know
来知道我们在哪 东西在哪 这之类
about how to find out about where we are, and where things are, and stuff like that.
周三再接着讲 到时见
So we'll pick that up on Wednesday, and I will see you then.
更多内容 请访问我校官网stanford.edu
> For more, please visit us at Stanford.edu.